<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<quotes>
  <quote author="Phil Grabsky, writer – An Inconvenient History, BBC">The dominant Catholic Church jumped through legalistic hoops to make slavery not only acceptable but justifiable as a way of spreading the faith.  Indeed, slave owners were obliged by law to baptise their slaves.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous, often attributed to Dan Quayle">If we don't succeed, we run the risk of failure.</quote>
  <quote author="Hob Broun">Realism...has no more to do with reality than anything else.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen Roberts">I contend that we are both Atheists.  I just believe in one fewer god than you do.  When you understand why you dismiss all the other possible gods, you will understand why I dismiss yours.</quote>
  <quote author="Cal Thomas, director of communications for Moral Majority, said his group did not open meetings with prayer because it is a political organization that includes Jews, Catholics, Mormons, Protestants, and some non-religious members.  What kind of prayer would we use? he asked.  Quoted from Falwell Arms the Opposition, San Francisco Chronicle, Sept. 19, 1982.">People for the American Way says it has yet to find anyone who has made a stronger case against the proposed school prayer Constitutional amendment.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin">Religion I found to be without any tendency to inspire, promote, or confirm morality, serves principally to divide us and make us unfriendly to one another.</quote>
  <quote author="Titus Maccius Plautus (254 BC - 184 BC), Miles Gloriosus">No man is wise enough by himself.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">All that is necessary, as it seems to me, to convince any reasonable person that the Bible is simply and purely of human invention—of barbarian invention—is to read it.  Read it as you would any other book; think of it as you would of any other; get the bandage of reverence from your eyes; drive from your heart the phantom of fear; push from the throne of your brain the cowled form of superstition—then read the Holy Bible, and you will be amazed that you ever, for one moment, supposed a being of infinite wisdom, goodness and purity, to be the author of such ignorance and of such atrocity.</quote>
  <quote author="Harry S Truman, 33rd U.S. President (1945-1953) quoted in The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">We have gone a long way toward civilization and religious tolerance, and we have a good example in this country.  Here the many Protestant denominations, the Catholic Church and the Greek Orthodox Church do not seek to destroy one another in physical violence just because they do not interpret every verse of the Bible in exactly the same way.  Here we now have the freedom of all religions, and I hope that never again will we have a repetition of religious bigotry, as we have had in certain periods of our own history.  There is no room for that kind of foolishness here.</quote>
  <quote author="Steve Allen">No actual tyrant known to history has ever been guilty of one-hundredth of the crimes, massacres, and other atrocities attributed to the Deity in the Bible.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken">I believe that religion, generally speaking, has been a curse to mankind — that its modest and greatly overestimated services on the ethical side have been more than overcome by the damage it has done to clear and honest thinking.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">The Christian God is a being of terrific character — cruel, vindictive, capricious, and unjust.</quote>
  <quote author="Henry David Thoreau (1817 - 1862)">Men are born to succeed, not fail.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein">True religion is real living; living with all one's soul, with all one's goodness and righteousness.</quote>
  <quote author="Madalyn Murray O'Hair, 1963 statement to the Supreme Court, Murray v. Curlett">An Atheist loves himself and his fellowman instead of a god.  An Atheist knows that heaven is something for which we should work now, here on earth, for all men together to enjoy.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, The Selfish Gene">Another meme of the religious meme complex is called faith.  It means blind trust, in the absence of evidence, even in the teeth of evidence.  The story of Doubting Thomas is told, not so that we shall admire Thomas, but so that we can admire the other apostles in comparison.  Thomas demanded evidence.  Nothing is more lethal for certain kinds of meme than a tendency to look for evidence.  The other apostles, whose faith was so strong that they did not need evidence, are held up to us as worthy of imitation.  The meme for blind faith secures its own perpetuation by the simple unconscious expedient of discouraging rational inquiry.</quote>
  <quote author="Art Spander">The great thing about democracy is that it gives every voter a chance to do something stupid.</quote>
  <quote author="Charles François Dupuis, 1794">A great error is more easily propagated, than a great truth, because it is easier to believe, than to reason, and because people prefer the marvels of romances to the simplicity of history.</quote>
  <quote author="Dr. Karl Menninger (1893 - 1990)">Set up as an ideal the facing of reality as honestly and as cheerfully as possible.</quote>
  <quote author="C.S. Lewis, noted Christian author">Of all bad men, religious bad men are the worst.</quote>
  <quote author="Clarence Darrow, The Sign, 1938">In spite of all the yearnings of men, no one can produce a single fact or reason to support the belief in God and in personal immortality.</quote>
  <quote author="Steven Weinberg, in Freethought Today, April, 2000">Religion is an insult to human dignity.  With or without it you would have good people doing good things and evil people doing evil things.  But for good people to do evil things, that takes religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Samuel McChord Crothers">Try as hard as we may for perfection, the net result of our labors is an amazing variety of imperfectness. We are surprised at our own versatility in being able to fail in so many different ways.</quote>
  <quote author="Gore Vidal (1925 - )">It is not enough to succeed. Others must fail.</quote>
  <quote author="Diane Frolov and Andrew Schneider, Northern Exposure, Cicely, 1992">You bluffed me! I don't like it when people bluff me. It makes me question my perception of reality.</quote>
  <quote author="Vladimir Lenin">Give me a child for the first 5 years of his life and he will be mine forever.</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin">The only good thing to come out of religion was the music.</quote>
  <quote author="Hugo L. Black, U.S. Supreme Court Justice, majority opinion in Everson v. Board of Education, 1947">No tax in any amount, large or small, can be levied to support any religious activities or institutions, whatever they may be called, or whatever form they may adopt to teach or practice religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Gerard V. Bradley, Notre Dame Law School Professor, in One Cheer for the Inquisitions on Catholic.net">The Myth of the Inquisition is just that: phony, made up, bogus.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, A Defense of the Constitutions of Government of the United States of America; from Adrienne Koch, ed., The American Enlightenment: The Shaping of the American Experiment and a Free Society, p. 258">The United States of America have exhibited, perhaps, the first example of governments erected on the simple principles of nature; and if men are now sufficiently enlightened to disabuse themselves of artifice, imposture, hypocrisy, and superstition, they will consider this event as an era in their history.  Although the detail of the formation of the American governments is at present little known or regarded either in Europe or in America, it may hereafter become an object of curiosity.  It will never be pretended that any persons employed in that service had interviews with the gods, or were in any degree under the influence of Heaven, more than those at work upon ships or houses, or laboring in merchandise or agriculture; it will forever be acknowledged that these governments were contrived merely by the use of reason and the senses....</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas R. Ybarra">A Christian is a man who feels repentance on a Sunday for what he did on Saturday and is going to do on Monday.</quote>
  <quote author="John F. Kennedy">I believe in an America where the separation of church and state is absolute — where no Catholic prelate would tell the president (should he be Catholic) how to act, and no Protestant minister would tell his parishioners for whom to vote — where no church or church school is granted any public funds or political preference — and where no man is denied public office merely because his religion differs from the president who might appoint him or the people who might elect him.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">The church has always been willing to swap off treasures in heaven for cash down.</quote>
  <quote author="Walter Savage Landor">Even the weakest disputant is made so conceited by what he calls religion, as to think himself wiser than the wisest who thinks differently from him.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson (Notes on Virginia, 1782)">Ignorance is preferable to error, and he is less remote from the truth who believes nothing than he who believes what is wrong.</quote>
  <quote author="Malcolm X (1925 - 1965), Malcolm X Speaks, 1965">Power never takes a back step - only in the face of more power.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech Humbolt">Ignorance worships mystery; reason explains it; the one grovels, the other soars.</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Winston Churchill (1874 - 1965)">When I am abroad, I always make it a rule never to criticize or attack the government of my own country. I make up for lost time when I come home.</quote>
  <quote author="Ulysses S. Grant">The art of war is simple enough. Find out where your enemy is. Get at him as soon as you can. Strike him as hard as you can, and keep moving on. </quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">I do not find in orthodox Christianity one redeeming feature.</quote>
  <quote author="Michel de Montaigne">Man is certainly stark mad; he cannot make a worm, yet he will make gods by the dozen.</quote>
  <quote author="Mogens Jallberg">In democracy it's your vote that counts; In feudalism it's your count that votes.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">All religions are inconsistent with mental freedom.  Shakespeare is my bible, Burns my hymn-book.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">Blasphemy?  No, it is not blasphemy.  If God is as vast as that, he is above blasphemy; if He is as little as that, He is beneath it.</quote>
  <quote author="Napoleon Bonaparte">Religion is what keeps the poor from murdering the rich.</quote>
  <quote author="Elbert Hubbard, lecturer, author, printer">When you once attribute effects to the will of a personal God, you have let in a lot of little gods and evils — then sprites, fairies, dryads, naiads, witches, ghosts and goblins, for your imagination is reeling, riotous, drunk, afloat on the flotsam of superstition.  What you know then doesn't count.  You just believe, and the more your believe the more do you plume yourself that fear and faith are superior to science and seeing.</quote>
  <quote author="Garrison Keillor (1942 - )">I believe in looking reality straight in the eye and denying it.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Heinlein, Time Enough for Love">Men rarely (if ever) dream up a god superior to themselves.  Most gods have the manners and morals of a spoiled child.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech Superstition">Ignorance is the soil in which belief in miracles grows.</quote>
  <quote author="from Article VI of the U.S. Constitution">... no religious Test shall ever be required as a Qualification to any Office or public Trust under the United States.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Francis Burton, explorer and writer (1821-1890)">The more I study religions the more I am convinced that man never worshipped anything but himself.</quote>
  <quote author="Peter Stone">When talking about unicorns, minotaurs, or compassionate conservatives, one does not normally have to prove their non-existence; the mere lack of any evidence is sufficient reason not to believe in any of them.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">Religion began when the first scoundrel met the first fool.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Lyon">If at first you don't succeed, find out if the loser gets anything.</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker">It is a fact of history and of current events that human beings exaggerate, misinterpret, or wrongly remember events.  They have also fabricated pious fraud.  Most believers in a religion understand this when examining the claims of other religions.</quote>
  <quote author="Reverend Pat Robertson">The feminist agenda is not about equal rights for women.  It is about a socialist, anti-family political movement that encourages women to leave their husbands, kill their children, practice witchcraft, destroy capitalism, and become lesbians.</quote>
  <quote author="H. L. Mencken (1880 - 1956)">The older I grow the more I distrust the familiar doctrine that age brings wisdom.</quote>
  <quote author="E. B. White (1899 - 1985), New Yorker, July 3, 1944">Democracy is the recurrent suspicion that more than half of the people are right more than half the time.</quote>
  <quote author="Susan B. Anthony">I distrust those people who know so well what God wants them to do because I notice it always coincides with their own desires.</quote>
  <quote author="Sigmund Freud">Religion is the process of unconscious wish fulfillment, where, for certain people, if the process did not take place it would put them in self-danger of coming to mental harm, being unable to cope with the idea of a godless, purposeless life.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell">Most people would sooner die than think; in fact, they do so.</quote>
  <quote author="Samuel Johnson">Prejudice, not being founded on reason, cannot be removed by argument.</quote>
  <quote author="Lyndon Johnson (1908-1973), 36th U.S. President, in The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">I believe in the American tradition of separation of church and state which is expressed in the First Amendment to the Constitution.  By my office — and by personal conviction — I am sworn to uphold that tradition.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">If God did not exist, it would be necessary to invent him; let us worship God through Jesus if we must — if ignorance has so far prevailed that this name can still be spoken in all seriousness without being taken as a synonym for rapine and carnage.  Every sensible man, every honourable man, must hold the Christian sect in horror...</quote>
  <quote author="William Saroyan (1908 - 1981)">Good people are good because they've come to wisdom through failure.</quote>
  <quote author="Rev. Gregory A. Boyd, Woodland Hills Church, Maplewood, MN">America wasn’t founded as a theocracy.  America was founded by people trying to escape theocracies.  Never in history have we had a Christian theocracy where it wasn’t bloody and barbaric.  That’s why our Constitution wisely put in a separation of church and state.</quote>
  <quote author="Bishop John Shelby Spong">Prayer cannot be a request made to a theistic deity to act in human history in a particular way.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, The Blind Watchmaker">Natural selection is the blind watchmaker, blind because it does not see ahead, does not plan consequences, has no purpose in view.  Yet the living results of natural selection overwhelmingly impress us with the appearance of design as if by a master watchmaker, impress us with the illusion of design and planning..</quote>
  <quote author="The American Association for the Advancement of Science">Evolution is one of the most robust and widely accepted principles of modern science.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Jefferson's Works, Vol. II., p. 217">Fix Reason firmly in her seat, and call to her tribunal every fact, every opinion.  Question with boldness even the existence of a God; because, if there be one, he must more approve the homage of reason than of blindfolded fear. ...  Do not be frightened from this inquiry by any fear of its consequences.  If it end in a belief that there is no God, you will find incitements to virtue in the comfort and pleasantness you feel in its exercise and in the love of others which it will procure for you</quote>
  <quote author="Rev. Jerry Falwell Founder of Moral Majority, Address to the Religious Newswriters Association in New Orleans, explaining why Moral Majority meetings do not open with prayer.">If we ever opened a meeting with a prayer, silent or otherwise, we would disintegrate.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">Let's get up off our knees, stop cringing before bogeymen and virtual fathers, face reality, and help science to do something constructive about human suffering.</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker in Losing Faith in Faith: From Preacher to Atheist, 1992">I have something to say to the religionist who feels atheists never say anything positive: You are an intelligent human being.  Your life is valuable for its own sake.  You are not second-class in the universe, deriving meaning and purpose from some other mind.  You are not inherently evil — you are inherently human, possessing the positive rational potential to help make this a world of morality, peace and joy.  Trust yourself</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">Infidelity is liberty; all religion is slavery.</quote>
  <quote author="Sophocles (496 BC - 406 BC), Antigone">Wisdom outweighs any wealth.</quote>
  <quote author="Calvin Coolidge, 30th U.S. President, Inaugural Address, March 4, 1925">We cannot permit any inquisition either within or without the law or apply any religious test to the holding of office.  The mind of America must be forever free.</quote>
  <quote author="Janis Joplin">Don't compromise yourself.  You're all you've got.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">The truths of religion are never so well understood as by those who have lost the power of reasoning.</quote>
  <quote author="Gloria Steinem (b. 1934) American writer and political activist, quoted in Breaking the Last Taboo (1996), James A. Haught">By the year 2000 we will, I hope, raise our children to believe in human potential, not God.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine, ibid.">I do not believe in the creed professed by the Jewish church, by the Roman church, by the Greek church, by the Turkish church, by the Protestant church, nor by any church that I know of.  My own mind is my own church.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to Thomas Jefferson">I almost shudder at the thought of alluding to the most fatal example of the abuses of grief which the history of mankind has preserved — the Cross.  Consider what calamities that engine of grief has produced!</quote>
  <quote author="David Miles, Orange Beach, AL">In contradiction to the Bible, the First Amendment to our Constitution gives us the right to worship gods (or not), work on Sunday (or not), and say what we wish about the various gods.  The Constitution, conceived by what may be the most brilliant and visionary group of men ever assembled, must take precedence over a book compiled by self-serving peoples of ancient cultures.</quote>
  <quote author="Alan Corenk">Democracy consists of choosing your dictators, after they've told you what you think it is you want to hear.</quote>
  <quote author="Woodrow Wilson (1856 - 1924), letter to Mary A. Hulbert, September 21, 1913">Power consists in one's capacity to link his will with the purpose of others, to lead by reason and a gift of cooperation.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">This crime called blasphemy was invented by priests for the purpose of defending doctrines not able to take care of themselves.</quote>
  <quote author="Ken Ham, founder of Answers in Genesis">If you can't trust the Bible's history, how can you trust its morality?</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Aug. 15, 1820">To talk of immaterial existences, is to talk of nothings.  To say that the human soul, angels, God are immaterial is to say, they are nothings, or that there is no God, no angels, no soul.  I cannot reason otherwise: ...  I believe I am supported in my creed of materialism by [John] Locke.</quote>
  <quote author="Woody Allen">If it turns out that there is a God, I don't think that he's evil.  But the worst that you can say about him is that basically he's an underachiever.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, Unweaving the Rainbow">I believe that an orderly universe, one indifferent to human preoccupations, in which everything has an explanation even if we still have a long way to go before we find it, is a more beautiful, more wonderful place than a universe tricked out with capricious ad hoc magic.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen Hawking">God is ... the embodiment of the laws of the universe.</quote>
  <quote author="George Bernard Shaw (1856 - 1950), Man and Superman (1903) &quot;Maxims for Revolutionists&quot;">Democracy substitutes election by the incompetent many for appointment by the corrupt few.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Moyers">Theology asserts propositions that cannot be proven true; ideologues hold stoutly to a worldview despite being contradicted by what is generally accepted as reality.  When ideology and theology couple, their offspring are not always bad but they are always blind.  And there is the danger: voters and politicians alike, oblivious to the facts.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Feynman, The Pleasure of Finding Things Out (1981)">Start out understanding religion by saying everything is possibly wrong. . . . As soon as you do that, you start sliding down an edge which is hard to recover from. . . .</quote>
  <quote author="Abu'l-Ala-Al-Ma'arri, 973-1057 C.E., Syrian poet">The world holds two classes of men – intelligent men without religion, and religious men without intelligence.</quote>
  <quote author="Ella Wheeler Wilcox, poet (1850-1919)">So many gods, so many creeds, so many paths that wind and wind, while just the art of being kind is all the sad world needs.</quote>
  <quote author="W. L. George">Wars teach us not to love our enemies, but to hate our allies. </quote>
  <quote author="G. K. Chesterson">The test of a good religion is whether you can joke about it.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine, The Age of Reason">The study of theology, as it stands in Christian churches, is the study of nothing; it is founded on nothing; it rests on no principles; it proceeds by no authorities; it has no data; it can demonstrate nothing; and it admits of no conclusion.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">With soap, baptism is a good thing.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell">The good life is one inspired by love and guided by knowledge.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">Reason must be deluded, blinded, and destroyed.  Faith must trample underfoot all reason, sense, and understanding, and whatever it sees must be put out of sight and ... know nothing but the word of God.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther King, Jr.">Nothing in the world is more dangerous than sincere ignorance and conscientious stupidity.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen Hawking">The greatest enemy of knowledge is not ignorance, it is the illusion of knowledge.</quote>
  <quote author="Prof Carl Lofmark, What is the Bible?">God himself shows little respect for what is best in the Bible.  He commands 'Thou shalt not kill', and then promptly orders the killing of many thousands.  Moses condemns human sacrifice but God demands the sacrifice of Isaac and accepts that of Jephthah's daughter.  Jesus preaches 'whoever shall say 'you fool!', shall be in danger of hell fire', but shortly after this rages at the pharisees saying 'you fools!'.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein, from The Human Side, edited by Helen Dukas and Banesh Hoffman">It was, of course, a lie what you read about my religious convictions, a lie which is being systematically repeated.  I do not believe in a personal God and I have never denied this but have expressed it clearly.  If something is in me which can be called religious then it is the unbounded admiration for the structure of the world so far as our science can reveal it.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">The few have said, Think!  The many have said, Believe!  The first doubt was the womb and cradle of progress, and from the first doubt, man has continued to advance.</quote>
  <quote author="Phillip Johnson, creator of the idea of 'Intelligent' Design">The objective is to convince people that Darwinism is inherently atheistic, thus shifting the debate from creationism vs. evolution to the existence of God vs. the non-existence of God.  From there people are introduced to the truth of the Bible and then the question of sin and finally introduced to Jesus.</quote>
  <quote author="Woodrow Wilson (1856 - 1924)">The flag is the embodiment, not of sentiment, but of history.</quote>
  <quote author="Mickey Rooney (1920 - )">You always pass failure on the way to success.</quote>
  <quote author="Madalyn Murray O'Hair">Atheism is based upon a materialist philosophy, which holds that nothing exists but natural phenomena.  There are no supernatural forces or entities, nor can there be any.  Nature simply exists.</quote>
  <quote author="Daniel Dennett, Darwin’s Dangerous Idea: Evolution and the Meanings of Life">There are no forces on this planet more dangerous to all of us than the fanaticisms of fundamentalism.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech The Ghosts">Take from the church the miraculous, the supernatural, the unreasonable the impossible, the unknowable, and the absurd, and nothing but a vacuum remains... Religion has not civilized man — man has civilized religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Chapman Cohen">ATHEIST is really a thoroughly honest, unambiguous term; it admits of no paltering and of no evasion, and the need of the world, now as ever, is for clear-cut issues and unambiguous speech.</quote>
  <quote author="Ulysses S. Grant, address to the Army of the Tennessee, Des Moines, Iowa, September 25, 1875, from The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">Encourage free schools and resolve that not one dollar appropriated for their support shall be appropriated to the support of any sectarian schools.  Resolve that neither the state nor nation, nor both combined, shall support institutions of learning other than those sufficient to afford every child growing up in the land of opportunity of a good common school education, unmixed with sectarian, pagan, or Atheistical dogmas.  Leave the matter of religion to the family altar, the church and the private school supported entirely by private contributions.  Keep the church and state forever separate.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to John Taylor">The priesthood have, in all ancient nations, nearly monopolized learning.  And ever since the Reformation, when or where has existed a Protestant or dissenting sect who would tolerate A FREE INQUIRY?  The blackest billingsgate, the most ungentlemanly insolence, the most yahooish brutality, is patiently endured, countenanced, propagated, and applauded.  But touch a solemn truth in collision with a dogma of a sect, though capable of the clearest proof, and you will find you have disturbed a nest, and the hornets will swarm about your eyes and hand, and fly into your face and eyes.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, letter to Dr. Thomas Cooper, February 10, 1814">Christianity neither is, nor ever was a part of the common law.</quote>
  <quote author="Barry Goldwater">Now those who seek absolute power, even though they seek it to do what they regard as good, are simply demanding the right to enforce their own version of heaven on earth, and let me remind you they are the very ones who always create the most hellish tyranny.</quote>
  <quote author="Jesus, Mythical founder-figure of the Christian religions">Render therefore unto Caesar the things which are Caesar's; and unto God the things that are God's. (Matthew 22:21).</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Browning (1812 - 1889)">A minute's success pays the failure of years.</quote>
  <quote author="Homer (800 BC - 700 BC), The Iliad">It is not unseemly for a man to die fighting in defense of his country.</quote>
  <quote author="George Santayana, philosopher (1863-1952), Little Essays, No. 107, Christian Morality">Christianity persecuted, tortured, and burned.  Like a hound it tracked the very scent of heresy.  It kindled wars, and nursed furious hatreds and ambitions.  It sanctified, quite like Mohammedanism, extermination and tyranny. . .”.</quote>
  <quote author="Eugene McCarthy (1916 - 2005)">Being in politics is like being a football coach. You have to be smart enough to understand the game, and dumb enough to think it's important.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">Drive them [Jews] like mad dogs from our land... let not one of them live...</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, (ibid.)">Some volumes against Deism fell into my hands … they produced an effect precisely the reverse to what was intended by the writers; for the arguments of the Deists, which were cited in order to be refuted, appeared to me much more forcibly than the refutation itself; in a word, I soon became a thorough Deist.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to Thomas Jefferson">The question before the human race is, whether the God of nature shall govern the world by his own laws, or whether priests and kings shall rule it by fictitious miracles?</quote>
  <quote author="William Hazlitt (1778 - 1830)">The love of liberty is the love of others; the love of power is the love of ourselves.</quote>
  <quote author="James Boswell (1740 - 1795), Life of Samuel Johnson, 1791">Men are wise in proportion, not to their experience, but to their capacity for experience.</quote>
  <quote author="The Panda's Thumb">There is nothing wrong with challenging conventional wisdom — continuing challenge is a core feature of science.  But challengers should at least be aware of, read, cite, and specifically rebut the actual data that supports conventional wisdom, not merely construct a rhetorical edifice out of omission of relevant facts, selective quoting, bad analogies, knocking down strawmen, and tendentious interpretations.  Unless and until the 'intelligent design' movement does this, they are not seriously in the game.  They're not even playing the same sport.</quote>
  <quote author="Walt Whitman (1819 - 1892)">Have you heard that it was good to gain the day? I also say it is good to fall, battles are lost in the same spirit in which they are won.
	</quote>
  <quote author="George Washington, 1st U.S. President">The United States of America should have a foundation free from the influence of clergy.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">The distribution of species on islands and continents throughout the world is exactly what you'd expect if evolution was a fact.  The distribution of fossils in space and in time are exactly what you would expect if evolution were a fact.  There are millions of facts all pointing in the same direction and no facts pointing in the wrong direction.</quote>
  <quote author="Joseph Lewis, American Freethinker">Let me tell you that religion is the cruelest fraud ever perpetrated upon the human race.  It is the last of the great schemes of thievery that man must legally prohibit so as to protect himself from the charlatans who prey upon the ignorance and fears of the people.</quote>
  <quote author="Carl Jung (1875 - 1961)">
		Nothing has a stronger influence psychologically on their environment and especially on their children than the unlived life of the parent.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, in his Statute for Religious Freedom, saying government has no authority over one's religious opinions, thus defining crime as the injury of a person or his property">The legitimate powers of government extend to such acts only as are injurious to others.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Browning">Who knows most, doubts most.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">For ages, a deadly conflict has been waged between a few brave men and women of thought and genius upon the one side, and the great ignorant religious mass on the other.  This is the war between Science and Faith.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">What is it the Bible teaches us? — raping, cruelty, and murder.  What is it the New Testament teaches us? - to believe that the Almighty committed debauchery with a woman engaged to be married, and the belief of this debauchery is called faith.</quote>
  <quote author="Marrila M. Ricker (1840-1920)">If you must believe in anything, believe in yourselves, in your senses, in your minds.  To accept a religious creed is to accept another mind in place of your own and generally contrary to your own.  When religious belief comes in brains go out</quote>
  <quote author="Anon..">The quest for God is like a blind man in a dark room looking for a black cat that isn't there.</quote>
  <quote author="Robbie Gass">
		Like an ability or a muscle, hearing your inner wisdom is strengthened by doing it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Menander (342 BC - 292 BC), Unidentified fragment">
		It is not white hair that engenders wisdom.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Vladimir Lenin">Autocracy cannot do without its twin agents: a hangman and a priest, the first to suppress popular resistance by force, the second to sweeten and embellish the lot of the oppressed with empty promises of a heavenly kingdom.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln (1809 - 1865)">
		Nearly all men can stand adversity, but if you want to test a man's character, give him power.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Georg Christoph Lichtenberg (1742 - 1799)">
		One's first step in wisdom is to question everything - and one's last is to come to terms with everything.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Jane Wagner, (and Lily Tomlin)">
		Reality is the leading cause of stress amongst those in touch with it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Leo Tolstoy">Freethinkers are those who are willing to use their minds without prejudice and without fearing to understand things that clash with their own customs, privileges, or beliefs.  This state of mind is not common, but it is essential for right thinking; where it is absent, discussion is apt to become worse than useless.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison">When indeed Religion is kindled into enthusiasm, its force like that of other passions is increased by the sympathy of a multitude.  But enthusiasm is only a temporary state of Religion, and whilst it lasts will hardly be seen with pleasure at the helm.  Even in its coolest state, it has been much oftener a motive to oppression than a restraint from it.</quote>
  <quote author="Salman Rushdie, author">In India, as elsewhere in our darkening world, religion is the poison in the blood.  Where religion intervenes, mere innocence is no excuse.  Yet we go on skating around this issue, speaking of religion in the fashionable language of 'respect.'  What is there to respect in any of this, or in any of the crimes now being committed almost daily around the world in religion's dreaded name?</quote>
  <quote author="C. S. Lewis, famous Christian apologist and former Atheist">I was at this time living, like so many Atheists or Antitheists, in a whirl of contradictions.  I maintained that God did not exist.  I was also very angry with God for not existing.  I was equally angry with Him for creating a world.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein, letter to Edgar Meyer, Jan. 2, 1915">I see only with deep regret that God punishes so many of His children for their numerous stupidities, for which only He Himself can be held responsible; in my opinion, only His nonexistence could excuse Him.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, (Franklin's Autobiography, 1817–18)">Scarcely was I arrived at fifteen years of age, when, after having doubted in turn of different tenets, according as I found them combated in the different books that I read, I began to doubt of Revelation itself.</quote>
  <quote author="Philip K. Dick (1928 - 1982), Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?">
		Reality is that which, when you stop believing in it, doesn't go away.
	</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, 1823">The settled opinion here is that religion is essentially distinct from Civil Govt. and exempt from its cognizance; that a connection between them is injurious to both….</quote>
  <quote author="Homer J. Simpson">Suppose we've chosen the wrong god?  Every time we go to church, we're just making him madder and madder.</quote>
  <quote author="Marilyn vos Savant">
		To acquire knowledge, one must study; but to acquire wisdom, one must observe.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John B. Hodges">Religion is for people who have never matured in their understanding of ethics.  Religion teaches a child's view of ethics, that 'being good' means 'obeying your parent.'  It gives a moral blank check to those bold enough, dishonest enough, to claim to speak for God.  Atheism means looking at ethical questions as an adult among other adults, considering ethics as a means of maintaining peace and cooperation among equals, so that all may pursue happiness within the limits that ethics defines.</quote>
  <quote author="Penn &amp; Teller">Read the Bible, because we need more Atheists!</quote>
  <quote author="R. A. Butler (1902 - 1982)">
		In politics you must always keep running with the pack. The moment that you falter and they sense that you are injured, the rest will turn on you like wolves.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">Creationism: God's gift to the ignorant.</quote>
  <quote author="Andrew Jackson (1767-1845), 7th U.S. President (1829-1837), 1832 statement refusing to proclaim a national day of fasting and prayer, Correspondence 4:447">I could not do otherwise without transcending the limits prescribed by the Constitution for the President and without feeling that I might in some degree disturb the security which religion nowadays enjoys in this country in its complete separation from the political concerns of the General Government.</quote>
  <quote author="Senator Barry Goldwater">I am a conservative Republican, but I believe in democracy and the separation of church and state.  The conservative movement is founded on the simple tenet that people have the right to live life as they please as long as they don't hurt anyone else in the process.</quote>
  <quote author="Kate, on atheistempire@yahoogroups.com">There is no shortcut to intellectual honesty.  Atheism requires sacrifice — in that you sacrifice the illusion of immortality and the sense of transcendent purpose.  But, religion requires the sacrifice of critical thinking, self determination, your time, your money, and logic.</quote>
  <quote author="Will Rogers (1879 - 1935)">
		On account of being a democracy and run by the people, we are the only nation in the world that has to keep a government four years, no matter what it does.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Ron Reagan, son of President Ronald Reagan">People who believe they are acting with the mandate of God, who see others who don't share their beliefs as inferior in the eyes of God, make dangerous leaders.  Just ask Osama Bin Laden.</quote>
  <quote author="Tertullian (b. ca. 150-160, d. ca. 220-240), one of the writers of the early Christian Church">I believe BECAUSE it's impossible.</quote>
  <quote author="Elizabeth Cady Stanton">Only those who have lived all their lives under the dark clouds of vague, undefined fears can appreciate the joy of a doubting soul suddenly born into the kingdom of reason and free thought.</quote>
  <quote author="Erich Fromm">If faith cannot be reconciled with rational thinking, it has to be eliminated as an anachronistic remnant of earlier stages of culture and replaced by science dealing with facts and theories which are intelligible and can be validated.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, The Blind Watchmaker p. 6">Darwin made it possible to be an intellectually fulfilled atheist.</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, ibid.">Just as Christianity must destroy reason before it can introduce faith, so it must destroy happiness before it can introduce salvation.</quote>
  <quote author="St. Paul, Romans 2:1">You, therefore, have no excuse, you who pass judgment on someone else, for at whatever point you judge the other, you are condemning yourself, because you who pass judgment do the same things.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Aquinas">Unbelief is the greatest of sins.</quote>
  <quote author="H. L. Mencken (1880 - 1956)">
		Democracy is the theory that the common people know what they want and deserve to get it good and hard.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to John Adams (January 24, 1814)">The whole history of these books [the Gospels] is so defective and doubtful that it seems vain to attempt minute enquiry into it; and such tricks have been played with their text, and with the texts of other books relating to them, that we have a right,from that cause, to entertain much doubt what parts of them are genuine.  In the New Testament there is internal evidence that parts of it have proceeded from an extraordinary man; and that other parts are of the fabric of very inferior minds.  It is as easy to separate those parts, as to pick out diamonds from dunghills.</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Winston Churchill (1874 - 1965)">
		Success is the ability to go from one failure to another with no loss of enthusiasm.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams (1735 - 1826), Letter to Benjamin Rush, 18 April 1808">
		Our obligations to our country never cease but with our lives.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, ibid.">To an honest judge, the alleged convergence between religion and science is a shallow, empty, hollow, spin-doctored sham.</quote>
  <quote author="Gustave Flaubert (1821 - 1880)">
		The whole dream of democracy is to raise the proletarian to the level of stupidity attained by the bourgeois.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Adolf Hitler, April 26, 1933, from a speech made during negotiations leading to the Nazi-Vatican Concordat of 1933">Secular schools can never be tolerated because such a school has no religious instruction and a general moral instruction without a religious foundation is built on air; consequently, all character training and religion must be derived from faith . . . We need believing people.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln">You can fool some of the people all of the time, and all of the people some of the time, but you can not fool all of the people all of the time.</quote>
  <quote author="Mary Pickford (1893 - 1979)">
		If you have made mistakes, even serious ones, there is always another chance for you. What we call failure is not the falling down but the staying down.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker, of Freedom From Religion Foundation">If faith is a valid tool of knowledge, then anything can be true 'by faith,' and therefore nothing is true.  If the only reason you can accept a claim is by faith, then you are admitting that the claim does not stand on its own merits.</quote>
  <quote author="Ibn Warraq, Why I Am Not a Muslim">All religions are sick men's dreams, false — demonstrably false — and pernicious.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken">The whole aim of practical politics is to keep the populace alarmed – and hence clamorous to be led to safety — by menacing it with an endless series of hobgoblins, all of them imaginary.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, undated, Detached Memoranda">Strongly guarded as is the separation between Religion and Government in the Constitution of the United States, the danger of encroachment by Ecclesiastical Bodies may be illustrated by precedents already furnished in their short history.</quote>
  <quote author="Walt Whitman (1819 - 1892)">
		Wisdom is not finally tested in the schools, Wisdom cannot be pass'd from one having it to another not having it, Wisdom is of the soul, is not susceptible of proof, is its own proof.
	</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, Founding Father and author of the First Amendment">There is not a shadow of right in the general government to intermingle with religion.  Its least interference with it would be a most flagrant usurpation.</quote>
  <quote author="Chapman Cohen">Gods are fragile things; they may be killed by a whiff of science or a dose of common sense.</quote>
  <quote author="Randall Terry, April 15, 1993">Our goal is a Christian Nation....  We have a Biblical duty; we are called by God to conquer this country.  We don't want equal time.  We don't want Pluralism.  We want theocracy.  Theocracy means God rules.  I've got a hot flash.  God rules.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to Alexander Humboldt, 1813">History, I believe, furnishes no example of a priest-ridden people maintaining a free civil government.  This marks the lowest grade of ignorance, of which their political as well as religious leaders will always avail themselves for their own purposes.</quote>
  <quote author="The Catholic Church's Canon Law 1369">A person is to be punished with a just penalty, who . . . utters blasphemy, or gravely harms public morals, or rails at or excites hatred of or contempt for religion or the Church.</quote>
  <quote author="R. A. Butler (1902 - 1982)">
		Politics is largely a matter of heart.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Jonathan Swift, author/theologinian">It is useless to attempt to reason a man out of what he was never reasoned into.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell">When two men of science disagree, they do not invoke the secular arm; they wait for further evidence to decide the issue, because, as men of science, they know that neither is infallible.  But when two theologians differ, since there is no criteria to which either can appeal, there is nothing for it but mutual hatred and an open or covert appeal to force.</quote>
  <quote author="George S. Patton (1885 - 1945), (attributed)">
		Don't be a fool and die for your country. Let the other sonofabitch die for his.
	</quote>
  <quote author="OzHeretic Prepare Slaughter">Let's not forget that the first holocaust took place not in the concentration camps of Nazi Germany, or Poland, but on the cotton fields of Christian America, the gold mines of Catholic Brazil, and the sugar plantations of the Carribbean.  One and a half million negroes died in transit from their homeland.  We don't know how many were worked, whipped, tortured, hanged or beaten to death but the ultimate toll was considerably greater than the combined toll in Auswitz, Belsen and the like.  We're talking about the Christian holocaust.</quote>
  <quote author="Edward Abbey (1927-1989)">A patriot must always be ready to defend his country against its government.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln">I am for liberty of conscience in its noblest, broadest, and highest sense.  But I cannot give liberty of conscience to the pope and his followers, the papists, so long as they tell me, through all their councils, theologians, and canon laws that their conscience orders them to burn my wife, strangle my children, and cut my throat when they find their opportunity.</quote>
  <quote author="Unknown">If you can tell me what to think, then I can tell you where to go.</quote>
  <quote author="Laurence J. Peter (1919 - 1988)">
		Democracy is a process by which the people are free to choose the man who will get the blame.
	</quote>
  <quote author="D. James Kennedy, the most listened-to Presbyterian minister in the world today">Communistic evolution, according to the Senate committee that examined it, is responsible for 135 million deaths in peacetime.  There's no religion that has a tiny fraction of that many deaths on its conscience.  There are scientists who will admit that there's not one iota of scientific evidence to support it.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Maher">Religion is insanity by consensus.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, letter to William Short, Oct. 31, 1819">As you say of yourself, I too am an Epicurian.  I consider the genuine (not the imputed) doctrines of Epicurus as containing everything rational in moral philosophy which Greece and Rome have left us.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to Thomas Jefferson">[In regard to the Trinity]; Tom, had you and I been 40 days with Moses, and beheld the great God, and even if God himself had tried to tell us that three was one . . . and one equals three, you and I would never have believed it.  We would never fall victims to such lies.</quote>
  <quote author="Luther Burbank">Those who would legislate against the teaching of evolution should also legislate against gravity, electricity and the unreasonable velocity of light, and also, should introduce a clause to prevent the use of the telescope, the microscope and the spectroscope or any other instrument of precision which may in the future be invented, constructed or used for the discovery of truth.</quote>
  <quote author="Ulysses S. Grant">Leave the matter of religion to the family altar, the church, and the private schools, supported entirely by private contributions.  Keep the church and the state forever separated.</quote>
  <quote author="Mahatma Ghandi">There is no god higher than truth.</quote>
  <quote author="George Will">The problem with intelligent-design theory, is not that it is false but that it is not falsifiable: Not being susceptible to contradicting evidence, it is not a testable hypothesis.  Hence it is not a scientific but a creedal tenet — a matter of faith, unsuited to a public school's science curriculum.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">I was dead for millions of years before I was born and it never inconvenienced me a bit.</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Francis Bacon (1561 - 1626), Religious Meditations, Of Heresies, 1597">
		Knowledge is power.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark B. Cohen">
		Nothing can so alienate a voter from the political system as backing a winning candidate.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Theodore Herman Albert Dreiser">Religion is a bandage that man has invented to protect a soul made bloody by circumstance.</quote>
  <quote author="Michel Eyquem">For a desperate disease a desperate cure.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain, Following the Equator">We despise all reverences and all the objects of reverence which are outside the pale of our own list of sacred things.  And yet, with strange inconsistency, we are shocked when other people despise and defile the things which are holy to us.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Edison">Religion is all bunk.</quote>
  <quote author="George Bernard Shaw (1856 - 1950)">
		Democracy is a device that ensures we shall be governed no better than we deserve.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, Toward The Mystery">I have found Christian dogma unintelligible.  Early in life I absented myself from Christian assemblies.</quote>
  <quote author="Baruch Spinoza, Tractatus Theologico-Politicus (1670)">Philosophy has no end in view save truth; faith looks for nothing but obedience and piety.</quote>
  <quote author="Howard Stern, American radio personality, May 18, 2001, after his guest Leah Remini mentioned that she is a Scientologist">I don't think any religion makes any sense and I think people who are into that are really getting duped, and I don't think Judaism makes any more sense than Christianity, and I don't think Christianity makes any more sense than Scientology.  But here's a guy, L. Ron Hubbard, who told all his friends, 'Look, I'm gonna start a religion, 'cause I can't make any money as a science fiction writer.'  I mean, he admitted that publicly!  At least with Jesus Christ, you can't go talk to the guy.</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker">There is no evidence for a god, no coherent definition of a god, no good argument for a god, good positive arguments against a god, no agreement among believers about the nature or moral principles of a god, and no need for a god.  We can live happy, moral, productive lives without such belief, and we can do it better.</quote>
  <quote author="J. Krishnamurti">The mind gives meaning to anything but the meaning it gives is meaningless.</quote>
  <quote author="Denis Diderot (1713-1784)">Man will never be free until the last king is strangled with the entrails of the last priest.</quote>
  <quote author="Charles Schulz (1922-2000) American comic artist: creator of Peanuts to David Templeton in 1999, in My Lunch with Sparky (2000)">The term that best describes me now is 'secular humanist.'</quote>
  <quote author="A. Bartlett Giamatti (1938 - 1989), President of Yale University">
		Far better to think historically, to remember the lessons of the past. Thus, far better to conceive of power as consisting in part of the knowledge of when not to use all the power you have. Far better to be one who knows that if you reserve the power not to use all your power, you will lead others far more successfully and well.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Luther Burbank (1849-1926) Horticulturist">There is no other door to knowledge than the door Nature opens.  And there is no truth but the truth we discover in Nature.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein (1879 - 1955), (attributed)">
		Reality is merely an illusion, albeit a very persistent one.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Baron D'Holbach">All religions are ancient monuments to superstition, ignorance, ferocity; and modern religions are only ancient follies.</quote>
  <quote author="Clarence Darrow, Scopes trial, 1925">I do not consider it an insult, but rather a compliment to be called an agnostic.  I do not pretend to know where many ignorant men are sure — that is all that agnosticism means.</quote>
  <quote author="Mikhail Bakunin, ibid., p. 25">If God is, man is a slave; now, man can and must be free; then, God does not exist.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">The church is always trying to get other people to reform; it might not be a bad idea to reform itself a little, by way of example.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein (1879-1955) German-born American theoretical physicist, The World As I See It">I cannot imagine a God who rewards and punishes the objects of his creation, whose purposes are modeled after our own — a God, in short, who is but a reflection of human frailty.  Neither can I believe that the individual survives the death of his body, although feeble souls harbor such thoughts through fear or ridiculous egotisms.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther King, Jr.">Our lives begin to end the day we become silent about things that matter.</quote>
  <quote author="Francis Bellamy, The original Pledge of Allegiance, as it appeared in the issue of 'The Youth's Companion' (11/08/1892)">I pledge allegiance to my Flag and the Republic, for which it stands, one nation, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.</quote>
  <quote author="Randall Terry, founder of Operation Rescue">The Bible is the supreme law that all governments must obey.</quote>
  <quote author="Baruch Spinoza">I call him free who is led solely by reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">Of all the tyrannies that affect mankind, tyranny in religion is the worst; every other species of tyranny is limited to the world we live in; but this attempts to stride beyond the grave, and seeks to pursue us into eternity.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln, in a letter to a friend">The Bible is not my Book and Christianity is not my religion.  I could never give assent to the long complicated statements of Christian dogma.</quote>
  <quote author="Madalyn Murray O'Hair - Speech, 1990">Religion has ever been anti-human, anti-woman, anti-life, anti-peace, anti-reason and anti-science.  The god idea has been detrimental not only to humankind but to the earth.  It is time now for reason, education and science to take over.</quote>
  <quote author="Horace (65 BC - 8 BC), Odes">
		Force without wisdom falls of its own weight.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Henry Kissinger (1923 - )">
		The real distinction is between those who adapt their purposes to reality and those who seek to mold reality in the light of their purposes.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Elizabeth Cady Stanton">My religious superstition gave place to rational ideas based on scientific facts, and in proportion as I looked at everything from a new standpoint, I grew more happy day by day...</quote>
  <quote author="Infidel Guy">What is the purpose of prayer?  What can a finite being on Earth possibly tell an omnipotent, omniscient, Universe-creating deity that he/she/it doesn't know already?  If prayer actually worked, the Pope would live forever.</quote>
  <quote author="T. S. Eliot (1888 - 1965)">
		Humankind cannot stand very much reality.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">Faith is one of the world's great evils, comparable to the smallpox virus but harder to eradicate.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison - chief architect of the Constitution and the Bill of Rights">During almost fifteen centuries has the legal establishment of Christianity been on trial.  What has been its fruits?  More or less, in all places, pride and indolence in the clergy; ignorance and servility in the laity; in both, superstition, bigotry and persecution.</quote>
  <quote author="Aristotle (384 BC - 322 BC), Nichomachean Ethics">
		It is possible to fail in many ways...while to succeed is possible only in one way.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, Toward the Mystery">This is my religion . . . joy and exaltation in my own existence . . . so go ahead and snarl . . . bite . . . howl, you Calvinistic divines and all you who say I am no Christian.  I say you are not Christian.</quote>
  <quote author="John F. Kennedy (1917 - 1963), Inaugural address, January 20, 1961">
		And so, my fellow americans: ask not what your country can do for you - ask what you can do for your country. My fellow citizens of the world: ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to Dr. Woods">I have recently been examining all the known superstitions of the world, and do not find in our particular superstition (Christianity) one redeeming feature.  They are all alike, founded on fables and mythology.</quote>
  <quote author="Ambrose Bierce (1842 - 1914), The Devil's Dictionary">
		Politics, n. Strife of interests masquerading as a contest of principles.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine, ibid.">The most formidable weapon against errors of every kind is reason.  I have never used any other, and I trust I never shall.</quote>
  <quote author="Amy Tan (1952 - )">
		You see what power is - holding someone else's fear in your hand and showing it to them!
	</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin">I have as much authority as the Pope, I just don't have as many people who believe it.</quote>
  <quote author="Ayn Rand (1905-1982) American novelist and philosopher For the New Intellectual">The Founding Fathers were neither passive, death-worshiping mystics nor mindless, power-seeking looters; as a political group, they were a phenomenon unprecedented in history: they were thinkers who were also men of action.  They had rejected the soul-body dichotomy, with its two corollaries: the impotence of man's mind and the damnation of this earth; they had rejected the doctrine of suffering as man's metaphysical fate, they proclaimed man's right to the pursuit of happiness and were determined to establish on earth the conditions required for man's proper existence, by the 'unaided' power of their intellect.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams">The United States of America governments have exhibited, perhaps, the first example of governments erected on the simple principles of nature.  It will never be pretended that any persons employed in that service had interviews with the gods, or were in any degree under the influence of Heaven, more than those at work upon ships or houses, or laboring in merchandise or agriculture; it will forever be acknowledged that these governments were contrived merely by the use of reason and the senses.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">The Old Testament filled this world with tyranny and injustice, and the New gives us a future filled with pain for nearly all of the sons of men.  The Old Testament describes the hell of the past, and the New the hell of the future.</quote>
  <quote author="The Apostle Paul, in Romans 3:7 (KJV)">For if the truth of God hath more abounded through my lie unto his glory; why yet am I also judged as a sinner?</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison (1751-1836) 4th U.S. President (1809-1817) A Memorial and Remonstrance Against Religious Assessments, addressed to the Virginia General Assemby, 1785">Who does not see that the same authority, which can establish Christianity, in exclusion of all other Religions, may establish with the same ease any particular sect of Christians, in exclusion of all other Sects?</quote>
  <quote author="Ronald Reagan (1911 - 2004)">
		Politics is not a bad profession. If you succeed there are many rewards, if you disgrace yourself you can always write a book.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Barry Goldwater (1909-1998) Republican Senator from Arizona.  U.S. Senate Address, Sept. 16, 1981, in The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">Being a conservative in America traditionally has meant that one holds a deep, abiding respect for the Constitution.  We conservatives believe sincerely in the integrity of the Constitution.  We treasure the freedom that document protects.... By maintaining the separation of church and state, the United States has avoided the intolerance, which has so divided the rest of the world with religious wars.  Throughout our two hundred plus years, public policy debate has focused on political and economic issues, on which there can be compromise....  The great decisions of government cannot be dictated by the concerns of religious factions.  This was true in the days of Madison, and it is just as true today.  We have succeeded for 205 years in keeping the affairs of state separate from the uncompromising idealism of religious groups and we mustn't stop now.  To retreat from that separation would violate the principles of conservatism and the values upon which the framers built this democratic republic.</quote>
  <quote author="Jane Wagner, Lily Tomlin in &quot;The Search for Signs of Intelligent Life in the Universe&quot;">
		Reality is nothing but a collective hunch.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Winston Churchill">Never, never, never believe any war will be smooth and easy, or that anyone who embarks on the strange voyage can measure the tides and hurricanes he will encounter. The statesman who yields to war fever must realize that once the signal is given, he is no longer the master of policy but the slave of unforeseeable and uncontrollable events. </quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, quoted by Joseph Lewis in Benjamin Franklin - Freethinker">Indeed, when religious people quarrel about religion, or hungry people quarrel about victuals, it looks as if they had not much of either among them.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">Reason is the greatest enemy that faith has; it never comes to the aid of spiritual things, but more frequently than not struggles against the divine Word, treating with contempt all that emanates from God.</quote>
  <quote author="Anon.">Philosophy is questions that may never be answered.  Religion is answers that may never be questioned.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">It is error alone which needs the support of government.  Truth can stand by itself.</quote>
  <quote author="Harry Andrew Blackmun, U.S. Supreme Court Justice, majority opinion in Lee v. Weisman, 1992">The mixing of government and religion can be a threat to free government, even if no one is forced to participate....  When the government puts its imprimatur on a particular religion, it conveys a message of exclusion to all those who do not adhere to the favored beliefs.  A government cannot be premised on the belief that all persons are created equal when it asserts that God prefers some.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, 1896">When I became convinced that the universe is natural, that all the ghosts and gods are myths, there entered into my brain, into my soul, into every drop of my blood the sense, the feeling, the joy of freedom.  The walls of my prison crumbled and fell.  The dungeon was flooded with light and all the bolts and bars and manacles became dust.  I was no longer a servant, a serf, or a slave.  There was for me no master in all the wide world, not even in infinite space.  I was free — free to think, to express my thoughts—free to live my own ideal, free to live for myself and those I loved, free to use all my faculties, all my senses, free to spread imagination's wings, free to investigate, to guess and dream and hope, free to judge and determine for myself . . .  I was free!  I stood erect and fearlessly, joyously faced all worlds.</quote>
  <quote author="Father Frank Provone of Priests for Life, at a prayer breakfast during the 2000 Republican Convention">The Church does not dictate the policies of the nation.  The Church proclaims the truth of God to which all these policies must conform.</quote>
  <quote author="The original national motto">E Pluribus Unum (Out of many, one).</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein">The further the spiritual evolution of mankind advances, the more certain it seems to me that the path to genuine religiosity does not lie through the fear of life, and the fear of death, and blind faith, but through striving after rational knowledge.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, ibid.">The alternative which I favor is to renounce all euphemisms and grasp the nettle of the word atheism itself, precisely because it is a taboo word carrying frissons of hysterical phobia.  Critical mass may be harder to achieve than with some non-confrontational euphemism, but if we did achieve it with the dread word atheist, the political impact would be all the greater.</quote>
  <quote author="Margaret Knight">There is no justification for the common claim that Christianity was responsible for the abolition of slavery.  The Negro slave trade – a far more infamous practice than slavery in the ancient world – was initiated, carried on and defended by Christian men in Christian countries.</quote>
  <quote author="Henry Cate VII">
		The problem with political jokes is they get elected.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Paul Valery (1871 - 1945), Tel Quel 2 (1943)">
		Politics is the art of preventing people from taking part in affairs which properly concern them.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">What harm would it do, if a man told a good strong lie for the sake of the good and for the Christian church? [...] a lie out of necessity, a useful lie, a helpful lie, such lies would not be against God, he would accept them.</quote>
  <quote author="Hank Williams, Jr The American Dream">I've seen some preachers on TV in a shirt and a tie and a vest.  They say to send your money to the Lord - but they give you their address.</quote>
  <quote author="Cynthia Dwyer, American hostage held in Iran 444 days (1979-1981) February, 1981, The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">I learned how valuable our Constitution is and how valuable the separation of church and state is.</quote>
  <quote author="Bishop John Shelby Spong">The miracle stories of the New Testament can no longer be interpreted in a post-Newtonian world as supernatural events performed by an incarnate deity.</quote>
  <quote author="The U.S. Supreme Court, Stone v. Graham, 1980">The Ten Commandments are undeniably a sacred text in the Jewish and Christian faiths, and no legislative recitation of a supposed secular purpose can blind us to that fact ... the first part of the Commandments concerns the religious duties of believers: worshipping the Lord God alone, avoiding idolatry, not using the Lord's name in vain, and observing the Sabbath day.</quote>
  <quote author="Millard Fillmore (1800-1874) 13th U.S. President (1850-1853)">I am tolerant of all creeds.  Yet if any sect suffered itself to be used for political objects I would meet it by political opposition.  In my view church and state should be separate, not only in form, but fact.  Religion and politics should not be mingled.</quote>
  <quote author="Dr. Thomas Fuller (1654 - 1734), Gnomologia, 1732">
		Let not thy will roar, when thy power can but whisper.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Chapman Cohen, The Creedo of Empowerment">All my life I have made it a rule never to permit a religious man or woman take for granted that his or her religious beliefs deserved more consideration than non-religious beliefs or anti-religious ones.  I never agree with that foolish statement that I ought to respect the views of others when I believe them to be wrong.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert H. Jackson (1892-1954) Associate Justice, U.S. Supreme Court (1941-1954) dissenting opinion, Zorach v. Clauson, (April 28, 1952)">The day that this country ceases to be free for irreligion it will cease to be free for religion — except for the sect that can win political power.</quote>
  <quote author="W. K. Clifford, The Ethics of Belief, An Anthology of Atheism and Rationalism">It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone to believe anything upon insufficient evidence.</quote>
  <quote author="David Hume, Of Miracles pp.115-116">No testimony is sufficient to establish a miracle unless that testimony be of such a kind that its falsehood would be more miraculous than the fact which it endeavours to establish.</quote>
  <quote author="Harry Shearer">
		If absolute power corrupts absolutely, does absolute powerlessness make you pure?
	</quote>
  <quote author="James Watt, Interior Secretary under Ronald Reagan">We don't have to protect the environment — the Second Coming is at hand.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell (1872 - 1970)">
		Patriotism is the willingness to kill and be killed for trivial reasons.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mary Chase (1887 - 1973), Jimmy Stewart in &quot;Harvey&quot;, 1950">
		I've wrestled with reality for 35 years, Doctor, and I'm happy to state I finally won out over it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Charles Darwin">I can indeed hardly see how anyone ought to wish Christianity to be true; for if so the plain language of the text seems to show that the men who do not believe, and this would include my Father, Brother and almost all my best friends, will be everlastingly punished.  And that is a damnable doctrine.</quote>
  <quote author="Madalyn Murray O'Hair, to Christian audiences">You hate me because I am the embodiment of all your doubts.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, Poor Richard, 1758">The way to see by Faith is to shut the eye of Reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln, from What Great Men Think Of Religion by Ira Cardiff">It will not do to investigate the subject of religion too closely, as it is apt to lead to infidelity.</quote>
  <quote author="Titus Maccius Plautus (254 BC - 184 BC), Trinummus">
		Not by age but by capacity is wisdom acquired.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Clement Atlee">
		Democracy means government by discussion, but it is only effective if you can stop people talking.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">The bible has noble poetry in it; and some clever fables; and some blood-drenched history; and a wealth of obscenity; and upwards of a thousand lies.</quote>
  <quote author="Jules de Gaultier">
		Imagination is the one weapon in the war against reality.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Douglas Adams">God is no longer an explanation of anything, but has instead become something that would itself need an insurmountable amount of explaining.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, River out of Eden">Science shares with religion the claim that it answers deep questions about origins, the nature of life, and the cosmos.  But there the resemblance ends.  Scientific beliefs are supported by evidence, and they get results.  Myths and faiths are not and do not.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken (The New York Times Magazine, Sept. 11, 1955)">Faith may be defined briefly as an illogical belief in the occurrence of the improbable.</quote>
  <quote author="Charles W. Faulkner">When people expect God to plan their lives for them, and protect them, they tend to lose their motivation to guide and control their own lives.</quote>
  <quote author="John Locke, English philosopher">It is one thing to show a man that he is in error, and another to put him in possession of truth.</quote>
  <quote author="George Bernard Shaw">The fact that a believer is happier than a skeptic is no more to the point than the fact that a drunken man is happier than a sober one.  The happiness of credulity is a cheap and dangerous quality.</quote>
  <quote author="Steven Weinberg, ibid.">On balance the moral influence of religion has been awful</quote>
  <quote author="Ann Coulter">[Since 9/11] I am often asked if I still think we should invade their countries, kill their leaders, and convert them to Christianity.  The answer is: Now more than ever!</quote>
  <quote author="Anthony M. Kennedy (b. 1936) Supreme Court Justice, appointed by Reagan and confirmed 97-0, for the majority, Lee v. Weisman (1992), dismissing as unacceptable the cruel idea that a student should forfeit her own graduation in order to avoid commencement prayers and invocations, quoted from The Case Against School Prayer, a Freedom From Religion Foundation pamphlet">The lessons of the First Amendment are as urgent in the modern world as the 18th Century when it was written.  One timeless lesson is that if citizens are subjected to state-sponsored religious exercises, the State disavows its own duty to guard and respect that sphere of inviolable conscience and belief which is the mark of a free people.</quote>
  <quote author="Margaret Cho, weblog, 01-18-04">
		Politics has less to do with where you live than where your heart is.
	</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin">What's the point of fucking praying in the first place?  If God has a divine plan, what's the point of praying?  If what you want is in the divine plan, you will get it anyways... and if it's not, you won't get it because it's not in the divine plan.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to John Taylor">What havoc has been made of books through every century of the Christian era? Where are fifty gospels, condemned as spurious by the bull of Pope Gelasius? Where are the forty wagon-loads of Hebrew manuscripts burned in France, by order of another pope, because suspected of heresy?  Remember the 'index expurgatorius', the inquisition, the stake, the axe, the halter and the guillotine.</quote>
  <quote author="Will Rogers (1879 - 1935)">
		Politics is applesauce.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell, from an unpublished essay, Is There a God? (1952)">My conclusion is that there is no reason to believe any of the dogmas of traditional theology and, further, that there is no reason to wish that they were true.  Man, in so far as he is not subject to natural forces, is free to work out his own destiny.  The responsibility is his, and so is the opportunity.</quote>
  <quote author="Anne Nicol Gaylor, FFRF founder">There are no gods, no devils, no angels, no heaven or hell.  There is only our natural world.  Religion is but myth and superstition that hardens hearts and enslaves minds.</quote>
  <quote author="Baruch Spinoza, Ethics (1677)">Those who wish to seek out the cause of miracles, and to understand the things of nature as philosophers, and not to stare at them in astonishment like fools, are soon considered heretical and impious, and proclaimed as such by those whom the mob adores as the interpreters of nature and the gods.  For these men know that, once ignorance is put aside, that wonderment would be taken away, which is the only means by which their authority is preserved..</quote>
  <quote author="Adolf Hitler, Berlin, 1933, first radio address after coming to power">The National Government will preserve and defend those basic principles on which our nation has been built.  It regards Christianity as the foundation of our national morality, and the family as the basis of national life.</quote>
  <quote author="John Kenneth Galbraith (1908 - 2006)">
		Politics is not the art of the possible. It consists in choosing between the disastrous and the unpalatable.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Aristotle (ca. 384-322 B.C.E.) Greek philosopher, from 2000 Years of Disbelief, James A. Haught, ed.">A tyrant must put on the appearance of uncommon devotion to religion.  Subjects are less apprehensive of illegal treatment from a ruler whom they consider god-fearing and pious.  On the other hand, they do less easily move against him, believing that he has the gods on his side.</quote>
  <quote author="Isaac Asimov">Humanity has the stars in its future, and that future is too important to be lost under the burden of juvenile folly and ignorant superstition.</quote>
  <quote author="Isaac Asimov">To surrender to ignorance and call it God has always been premature, and it remains premature today.</quote>
  <quote author="Walter Goodman">The idea of all-out nuclear war is unsettling.</quote>
  <quote author="Lemuel Washburn">Most men would kill the truth if truth would kill their religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Reverend Reginald Howard Bass, The History of Natural Religion">An immoral god – a hangover from stone age minds – still corrupts human mentality with its scapegoat justice and the threat of eternal damnation.</quote>
  <quote author="Betty Bowers, America's Best Christian, of Landover Baptist Church">The actions taken by the New Hampshire Episcopalians (inducting a gay Bishop) are an affront to Christians everywhere.  I am just thankful that the church's founder, Henry VIII, and his wife Catherine of Aragon, and his wife Anne Boleyn, and his wife Jane Seymour, and his wife Anne of Cleves, and his wife Katherine Howard, and his wife Catherine Parr are no longer here to suffer through this assault on traditional Christian marriages.</quote>
  <quote author="unknown">Ethical people will do what is right, no matter what they are told.  Religious people will do what they are told, no matter what is right.</quote>
  <quote author="James A. Garfield (1831 - 1881)">
		Be fit for more than the thing you are now doing. Let everyone know that you have a reserve in yourself; that you have more power than you are now using. If you are not too large for the place you occupy, you are too small for it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln">To remain silent when one should protest makes cowards out of men.</quote>
  <quote author="Ernest Benn">
		Politics is the art of looking for trouble, finding it whether it exists or not, diagnosing it incorrectly, and applying the wrong remedy.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Abigail Van Buren (1918 - ), 1978">
		Wisdom doesn't automatically come with old age. Nothing does - except wrinkles. It's true, some wines improve with age. But only if the grapes were good in the first place.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Dalton Camp">
		Politics is made up largely of irrelevancies.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Lois McMaster Bujold, A Civil Campaign, 1999">
		If power was an illusion, wasn't weakness necessarily one also?
	</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein">The minority, the ruling class at present, has the schools and press, usually the Church as well, under its thumb.  This enables it to organize and sway the emotions of the masses, and make its tool of them.</quote>
  <quote author="Alfred E. Newman">
		Crime does not pay ... as well as politics.
	</quote>
  <quote author="George Jean Nathan (1882 - 1958)">
		Patriotism is often an arbitrary veneration of real estate above principles.
	</quote>
  <quote author="William G. McAdoo">It is impossible to defeat an ignorant man in argument.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">And to read the Bible without horror, we must undo everything that is tender, sympathising and benevolent in the heart of man.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Cosby (1937 - )">
		I don't know the key to success, but the key to failure is trying to please everybody.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Charles Darwin">Ignorance more frequently begets confidence than does knowledge: it is those who know little, and not those who know much, who so positively assert that this or that problem will never be solved by science.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Thomas">True believers are continually shown by reality that their god doesn't exist, but have developed extensive coping mechanisms to deal with this cognitive dissonance.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">In every country and every age, the priest had been hostile to Liberty.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to John Adams, 1823">The day will come when the mystical generation of Jesus, by the supreme being as his father in the womb of a virgin, will be classed with the fable of the generation of Minerva in the brain of Jupiter.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, River out of Eden, page 2">Since all organisms inherit all their genes from their ancestors, rather than from their ancestors' unsuccessful contemporaries, all organisms tend to possess successful genes.  They have what it takes to become ancestors — and that means to survive and reproduce.  This is why organisms tend to inherit genes with a propensity to build a well-designed machine — a body that actively works as if it is striving to become an ancestor.  That is why birds are so good at flying, fish so good at swimming, monkeys so good at climbing, viruses so good at spreading.  That is why we love life and love sex and love children.  It is because we all, without a single exception, inherit all of our genes from an unbroken line of successful ancestors.  The world becomes full of organisms that have what it takes to become ancestors.  That, in a sentence, is Darwinism.</quote>
  <quote author="Adolf Hitler, Mein Kampf">I am convinced that I am acting as the agent of our Almighty Creator.  By fighting the Jews, I am doing the Lord's work.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams">Nothing is more dreaded than the national government meddling with religion.</quote>
  <quote author="President Theodore Roosevelt">To announce that there must be no criticism of the president, or that we are to stand by the president, right or wrong, is not only unpatriotic and servile, but is morally treasonable to the American public.</quote>
  <quote author="Will Rogers (1879 - 1935), Illiterate Digest (1924), &quot;Breaking into the Writing Game&quot;">
		The more you read and observe about this Politics thing, you got to admit that each party is worse than the other. The one that's out always looks the best.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Harry S Truman">I never did give them hell.  I just told the truth, and they thought it was hell.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">Christianity is the most ridiculous, the most absurd, and bloody religion that has ever infected the world.</quote>
  <quote author="Samuel Johnson (1709 - 1784), quoted in Boswell's Life of Johnson">
		Patriotism is the last refuge of a scoundrel.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Walter Lippman">The radical novelty of modern science lies precisely in the rejection of the belief, which is at the heart of all popular religion, that the forces which move the stars and atoms are contingent upon the preferences of the human heart.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, ibid.">[It] is capable of driving people to such dangerous folly that faith seems to me to qualify as a kind of mental illness.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">There is one notable thing about our Christianity: bad, bloody, merciless, money-grabbing and predatory as it is — in our country particularly, and in all other Christian countries in a somewhat modified degree — it is still a hundred times better than the Christianity of the Bible, with its prodigious crime — the invention of Hell.  Measured by our Christianity of to-day, bad as it is, hypocritical as it is, empty and hollow as it is, neither the Deity nor His Son is a Christian, nor qualified for that moderately high place.  Ours is a terrible religion.  The fleets of the world could swim in spacious comfort in the innocent blood it has spilt.</quote>
  <quote author="Plato, philosopher (427-347 BCE)">The penalty that good men pay for not being interested in politics is to be governed by men worse than themselves.</quote>
  <quote author="Reverend Pat Robertson">If Christian people work together, they can succeed during this decade in winning back control of the institutions that have been taken from them over the past 70 years.  Expect confrontations that will be not only unpleasant but at times physically bloody.  When it is over, I am convinced God’s people will emerge victorious.</quote>
  <quote author="Joseph Farrell">
		The secret of all power is - save your force. If you want high pressure you must choke off waste.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Mann">War is a cowardly escape from the problems of peace. </quote>
  <quote author="Malcolm X (1925 - 1965)">
		You're not to be so blind with patriotism that you can't face reality. Wrong is wrong, no matter who does it or says it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Elie Wiesel (1928 - )">
		Ultimately, the only power to which man should aspire is that which he exercises over himself.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">If Christ were here there is one thing he would not be — a Christian.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to Mrs. M. Harrison Smith, 1816">I have ever judged of the religion of others by their lives…  But this does not satisfy the priesthood.  They must have a positive, a declared assent to all of their interested absurdities.  My opinion is that there would never have been an infidel, if there had never been a priest.</quote>
  <quote author="Larry Hardiman">
		The word 'politics' is derived from the word 'poly', meaning 'many', and the word 'ticks', meaning 'blood sucking parasites'.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Letter to nephew Peter Carr, 1787">Shake off all the fears of servile prejudices, under which weak minds are servilely crouched.  Fix reason firmly in her seat, and call on her tribunal for every fact, every opinion.  Question with boldness even the existence of God; because, if there be one, he must more approve of the homage of REASON than that of BLINDFOLDED fear.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin (1706-1790) American public official, writer, scientist, and printer.  Poor Richard's Almanack, 1758">The way to see by faith is to shut the eye of reason: The Morning Daylight appears plainer when you put out your Candle.</quote>
  <quote author="Eusebius, 4th century Bishop of Caesarea &amp; Church Historian, considered the Father of Eclessiastical History">I have repeated whatever may rebound to the glory, and suppressed all that could tend to the disgrace of our religion</quote>
  <quote author="George Bernard Shaw (1856 - 1950), &quot;Misalliance&quot;">
		You'll never have a quiet world till you knock the patriotism out of the human race.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Anon">The bible contains six admonishments to homosexuals and 362 admonishments to heterosexuals.  That doesn't mean that god doesn't love heterosexuals.  It's just that they need more supervision.</quote>
  <quote author="James Dobson, founder of Focus on the Family">Those who control what young people are taught, and what they experience — what they see, hear, think, and believe — will determine the future course for the nation.</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker, ibid, p. 360">There is not a single contemporary historical mention of Jesus, not by Romans or by Jews, not by believers or by unbelievers, during his entire lifetime.  This does not disprove his existence, but it certainly casts great doubt on the historicity of a man who was supposedly widely known to have made a great impact on the world.  Someone should have noticed.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">The prejudice of unfounded belief often degenerates into the prejudice of custom, and becomes at last rank hypocrisy.  When men, from custom or fashion or any worldly motive, profess or pretend to believe what they do not believe, nor can give any reason for believing, they unship the helm of their morality, and being no longer honest to their own minds they feel no moral difficulty in being unjust to others.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">It is between fifty and sixty years since I read the Apocalypse, and I then considered it merely the ravings of a maniac.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">I put the following work under your protection.  It contains my opinion upon religion.  You will do me the justice to remember, that I have always strenuously supported the right of every man to his opinion, however different that opinion might be to mine.  He who denies to another this right, makes a slave of himself to his present opinion, because he precludes himself the right of changing it.</quote>
  <quote author="Omphaloskeptic2@aol.com">Why would an all-powerful god become flesh in order to sacrifice himself to himself so that his creation might escape the wrath of himself.  Couldn't this god, in his infinite wisdom, come up with something a little more efficient?</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen J. Gould">[Evolution is] one of the best documented, most compelling and exciting concepts in all of science.</quote>
  <quote author="William Jefferson Bill Clinton, 42nd U.S. President">We have the most religious freedom of any country in the world, including the freedom not to believe.</quote>
  <quote author="William Howard Taft, 27th U.S. President (1909-1913), 10th Chief Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court (1921-1930), letter to Yale University, on turning down an offer for its presidency, in Breaking the Last Taboo (1996), from James A. Haught">I do not believe in the divinity of Christ, and there are many other of the postulates of the orthodox creed to which I cannot subscribe.</quote>
  <quote author="Plato (ca. B.C.E. 428-347) Greek philosopher, acknowledging that Atheists can lead an honest life, in Against the Faith (1985), p. 22, by Jim Herrick">For though a man should be a complete unbeliever in the being of gods; if he also has a native uprightness of temper, such persons will detest evil in men; their repugnance to wrong disinclines them to commit wrongful acts; they shun the unrighteous and are drawn to the upright.</quote>
  <quote author="Socrates">There is but one evil, ignorance.</quote>
  <quote author="Priestley's Benjamin Franklin Biography, p. 60">It is much to be lamented that a man of Franklin's general good character and great influence should have been an unbeliever in Christianity, and also have done as much as he did to make others unbelievers.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin (1706-1790), from the Historical Review of Pennsylvania, which warns, among other things, that if we don't use the Liberty to hold and express our own religious opinions, even if out of the fear of reprisal, then we rightly forfeit that Liberty">They that can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety deserve neither liberty nor safety.</quote>
  <quote author="Mikhail Bakunin, God and the State, 1871">The idea of God implies the abdication of human reason and justice; it is the most decisive negation of human liberty, and necessarily ends in the enslavement of mankind, both in theory and in practice.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, A Biography in his Own Words edited by Thomas Fleming, p. 404">As to Jesus of Nazareth, my Opinion of whom you particularly desire, I think the System of Morals and his Religion...has received various corrupting Changes, and I have, with most of the present dissenters in England, some doubts as to his Divinity; tho' it is a question I do not dogmatize upon, having never studied it, and think it needless to busy myself with it now, when I expect soon an opportunity of knowing the Truth with less trouble.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">Reason should be destroyed in all Christians.</quote>
  <quote author="Timothy LaHaye, co-author of the Left Behind series">We're in a religious war and we need to aggressively oppose secular humanism; these people are as religiously motivated as we are and they are filled with the devil.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">All prayers die in the air which they uselessly agitate.</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin, from the album A Place For My Stuff">I would never want to be a member of a group whose symbol was a guy nailed to two pieces of wood.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert A. Heinlein">It is a truism that almost any sect, cult, or religion will legislate its creed into law if it acquires the political power to do so.</quote>
  <quote author="George Bernard Shaw (1856 - 1950)">
		Patriotism is your conviction that this country is superior to all other countries because you were born in it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Ellen Herman, Northern Exposure, Only You, 1991">
		Joel: That's the movies, Ed. Try reality.Ed: No thanks.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Baltasar Gracian, The Art of Worldly Wisdom, 1647">
		The sole advantage of power is that you can do more good.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Kersey Graves, Sixteen Crucified Saviours">The present custom of orthodox Christendom, in packing their sins upon the back of a God, is just the same substantially as that of various heathen nations who were anciently in the habit of packing them upon the backs of various dumb animals.</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, Atheism: The Case Against God">The theist must present an intelligible description of god.  Until he does so, god makes no more sense than unie; both are cognitively empty, and any attempt at proof is logically absurd.</quote>
  <quote author="Seneca (5 BC - 65 AD)">
		Most powerful is he who has himself in his own power.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Kurt Vonnegut, Jr.">Say what you will about the sweet miracle of unquestioning faith.  I consider the capacity for it terrifying and absolutely vile.</quote>
  <quote author="Jeff Melvoin, Northern Exposure, Democracy in America, 1992">
		The idea of an election is much more interesting to me than the election itself...The act of voting is in itself the defining moment.
	</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, The Federalist Papers, Paper No. 10">A zeal for different opinions concerning religion...[has] divided mankind into parties, inflamed them with mutual animosity, and rendered them much more disposed to vex and oppress each other than to co-operate for their common good.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther">Whoever wants to be a Christian should tear the eyes out of his reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, Individuality (1873)">It is contended by many that ours is a Christian government, founded upon the Bible, and that all who look upon the book as false or foolish are destroying the foundation of our country.  The truth is, our government is not founded upon the rights of gods, but upon the rights of men.  Our Constitution was framed, not to declare and uphold the deity of Christ, but the sacredness of humanity.  Ours is the first government made by the people and for the people.  It is the only nation with which the gods have had nothing to do.  And yet there are some judges dishonest and cowardly enough to solemnly decide that this is a Christian country, and that our free institutions are based upon the infamous laws of Jehovah.</quote>
  <quote author="President George H.W. Bush">I don't know that Atheists should be considered as citizens, nor should they be considered patriots.  This is one nation under God.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln">I see a very dark cloud on America's horizon, and that cloud is coming from Rome.</quote>
  <quote author="Mike Ditka (1939 - )">
		Success isn't permanent, and failure isn't fatal.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Charles De Gaulle (1890 - 1970)">
		I have come to the conclusion that politics are too serious a matter to be left to the politicians.
	</quote>
  <quote author="President George W. Bush, a born-again Christian">On the issue of evolution, the verdict is still out on how God created the Earth.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams">The divinity of Jesus is made a convenient cover for absurdity.  Nowhere in the Gospels do we find a precept for Creeds, Confessions, Oaths, Doctrines, and whole carloads of other foolish trumpery that we find in Christianity.</quote>
  <quote author="Dan Barker, ibid">You believe in a book that has talking animals, wizards, witches, demons, sticks turning into snakes, food falling from the sky, people walking on water, and all sorts of magical, absurd and primitive stories, and you say that we are the ones that need help?</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson (1743-1826), 3rd U.S. President (1801-1809), letter to Danbury Baptists, 1802">Believing that religion is a matter which lies solely between man and his God, that he owes account to none other for his faith or his worship, that the legitimate powers of government reach actions only, and not opinions, I contemplate with sovereign reverence that act of the whole American people which declared that their Legislature should make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof, thus building a wall of separation between Church and State.</quote>
  <quote author="Margaret Knight, Lecturer on Psychology, Aberdeen University">Jesus, in fact, was typical of a certain kind of fanatical young idealist: at one moment holding forth with tears in his eyes about the need for universal love; at the next, furiously denouncing the morons, crooks and bigots who do not see eye to eye with him.  It is very natural and very human behaviour.  But it is not supernatural.  Many of the great men in history (for example Socrates and Gandhi) have met criticism with more dignity and restraint.</quote>
  <quote author="Epicurus (ca. 341-270 B.C.E.) Greek philosopher, quoted from Erik Hoepfinger, personal note to Cliff Walker">Is God willing to prevent evil, but not able?
Then he is not omnipotent.
Is he able, but not willing?
Then he is malevolent.
Is he both able and willing?
Then whence cometh evil?
Is he neither able nor willing?
Then why call him God?</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, letter to Ezra Stiles Ely, June 25, 1819">You say you are a Calvinist.  I am not.  I am of a sect by myself, as far as I know.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll (1833-1899) American politician">The God of hell should be held in loathing, contempt and scorn.  A god who threatens eternal pain should be hated, not loved; cursed, not worshipped.  A heaven presided over by such a god must be below the meanest hell.</quote>
  <quote author="Harley Sorensen, SF Gate">Those who get instructions directly from the Almighty are twice blessed.  They get their orders from the Highest Authority, and the orders are always to do what they would have done anyway.</quote>
  <quote author="George Washington">Religious controversies are always productive of more acrimony and irreconcilable hatreds than those which spring from any other cause.</quote>
  <quote author="Brian Flemming, director of the documentary movie, The God Who Wasn't There">I think that the United States is heading in the direction of theocracy.  The problem is that we let religious people say stunningly false things and we consider it rude to question those beliefs.  But we should be shunning those people.  If that sounds intolerant, that's the point.  I'm not tolerant of suspending reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Gates">Just in terms of allocation of time resources, religion is not very efficient.  There's a lot more I could be doing on a Sunday morning.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">I am very hostile to religion because it is enormously dominant, especially in American life.  And I don't buy the argument that, well, it's harmless.  I think it is harmful, partly because I care passionately about what's true.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell (1872 - 1970)">
		The whole problem with the world is that fools and fanatics are always so certain of themselves, but wiser people so full of doubts.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Kenneth Galbraith (1908 - 2006)">
		Nothing is so admirable in politics as a short memory.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Larry Mundinger, 1999">Morality is doing what is right no matter what you are told.  Religion is doing what you are told no matter what is right.</quote>
  <quote author="Tom Stoppard (1937 - ), Jumpers (1972) act 1">
		It's not the voting that's democracy, it's the counting.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Friedrich Nietzsche, (1844-1900)">Which is it, is man one of God's blunders or is God one of man's?</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, ibid.">Reason is not one tool of thought among many, it is the entire toolbox.  To advocate that reason be discarded in some circumstances is to advocate that thinking be discarded — which leaves one in the position of attempting to do a job after throwing away the required instrument.</quote>
  <quote author="Jimmy Wales, Keynote Speech, SXSW 2006">
		Most people assume the fights are going to be the left versus the right, but it always is the reasonable versus the jerks.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, Works, Vol. X', p. 323">The things of this world take up too much of my time, of which indeed I have too little left, to undertake anything like a reformation in religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Elizabeth Cady Stanton">I view it as one of the greatest crimes to shadow the minds of the young with these gloomy superstitions, and with fears of the unknown and the unknowable to poison all their joy in life.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">The gods offer no rewards for intellect.  There was never one yet that showed any interest in it.</quote>
  <quote author="Nathan Hale (1755 - 1776), last words, 22 September 1776 (attributed)">
		I only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Friedrich Nietzsche">After coming into contact with a religious man I always feel I must wash my hands.</quote>
  <quote author="Abbot Arnold de Citeaux, 1205 (during the Fourth Crusade)">Kill them all.  God will select those who should go to heaven and those who should go to hell.</quote>
  <quote author="Margaret Knight">This hideous doctrine of eternal torment after death has probably caused more terror and misery, more cruelty and more violation of natural human sympathy, than any belief in the history of mankind.  Yet this doctrine was taught unambiguously by Jesus.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, letter to Benjamin Vaughan, in Works, Vol. X, p.365">Do not, however, mistake me.  It is not to my good friend's heresy that I impute his honesty.  On the contrary, 'tis his honesty that brought upon him the character of a heretic.</quote>
  <quote author="George Washington (1732-1799) 1st U.S. President, letter to the members of the New Church in Baltimore, 1793, in Anson Phelps Stokes, Church and State in the United States, Vol 1. p. 497, quoted from The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">We have abundant reason to rejoice that in this Land the light of truth and reason has triumphed over the power of bigotry and superstition ... In this enlightened Age and in this Land of equal liberty it is our boast, that a man's religious tenets will not forfeit the protection of the Laws, nor deprive him of the right of attaining and holding the highest Offices that are known in the United States.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, The Devil's Chaplain (2004)">My last vestige of 'hands off religion' respect disappeared in the smoke and choking dust of September 11th 2001, followed by the 'National Day of Prayer,' when prelates and pastors did their tremulous Martin Luther King impersonations and urged people of mutually incompatible faiths to hold hands, united in homage to the very force that caused the problem in the first place.</quote>
  <quote author="Ernst Mayr, Harvard University, one of the most influential biologists in history">I have the honesty to say I’m an Atheist.  There is nothing that supports the idea of a personal God.</quote>
  <quote author="Lily Tomlin (1939 - )">
		Reality is a crutch for people who can't cope with drugs.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Mason, The Christian Holocaust">And so the violence continued century after century, fired by a Spirit which gloated with vindictive piety over the suffering of burning heretics on earth with superhuman malice upon their imagined suffering beyond the grave.</quote>
  <quote author="Sigmund Freud">Humanity is in the highest degree irrational, so that there is no prospect of influencing it by reasonable arguments.  Against prejudice one can do nothing.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">The clergy converted the simple teachings of Jesus into an engine for enslaving mankind and adulterated by artificial constructions into a contrivance to filch wealth and power to themselves...these clergy, in fact, constitute the real Anti-Christ.</quote>
  <quote author="Lily Tomlin">When we talk to God, we're praying.  When God talks to us, we're schizophrenic.</quote>
  <quote author="H.A.L. Fisher, History of Europe">It is a terrible commentary on Christian civilisation that the longest period of slave-raiding known to history was initiated by the action of Spain, Portugal, France, Holland and Britain, after the Christian faith had for more than a thousand years been the established religion of Europe.</quote>
  <quote author="Shadia B. Drury, Why Biblical Religions Are an Obstacle to Freedom">Far from being an aberration that is not representative of Christianity, the persecution of heretics follows logically from the connection of faith and salvation as presented by Jesus in the Gospels.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Taylor, Will Secularism Survive?, Free Inquiry">What I conclude is that religion has nothing to do with experience or reason but with deep and irrational needs.</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, ibid.">It cannot be emphasised too strongly that Christianity has a vested interest in human misery.  Christianity, perhaps more than any religion before or since, capitalized on human suffering; and it was enormously successful in insuring its own existence through the perpetuation of human suffering.</quote>
  <quote author="Francis Bacon">Atheism leaves a man to sense, to philosophy, to natural piety, to laws, to reputation; all of which may be guides to an outward moral virtue, even if religion vanished; but religious superstition dismounts all these and erects an absolute monarchy in the minds of men.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Edison">I have never seen the slightest scientific proof of the religious theories of heaven and hell, of future life for individuals, or of a personal God.</quote>
  <quote author="David Hume, ibid.">Superstition is an enemy to civil liberty.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">Whenever we read the obscene stories, the voluptuous debaucheries, the cruel and tortuous executions, the unrelenting vindictiveness with which more than half the Bible is filled, it would be more consistent that we call it the word of a demon than the word of God.  It is a history of wickedness that has served to corrupt and brutalize mankind.</quote>
  <quote author="John Lennon, Imagine">Imagine there's no heaven,
It's easy if you try.
No hell below us,
Above us only sky.
Imagine all the people, living for today. . .
Imagine there's no countries,
It isn't hard to do.
Nothing to kill or die for,
And no religion too.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, to Jefferson, 3 December 1813">Indeed, Mr. Jefferson, what could be invented to debase the ancient Christianism, which Greeks, Romans, Hebrews and Christian factions, above all the Catholics, have not fraudulently imposed upon the public?  Miracles after miracles have rolled down in torrents, wave succeeding wave in the Catholic church, from the Council of Nicea, and long before, to this day.</quote>
  <quote author="John F. Kennedy, address to the Ministerial Association of Greater Houston, September 12, 1960">I believe in an America that is officially neither Catholic, Protestant nor Jewish — where no public official either requests or accepts instructions on public policy from the pope, the National Council of Churches or any other ecclesiastical source — where no religious body seeks to impose its will directly or indirectly upon the general populace or the public acts of its officials.</quote>
  <quote author="Quintilian, De Institutione Oratoria">
		Those who wish to appear wise among fools, among the wise seem foolish.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">When one reads Bibles, one is less surprised at what the Deity knows than at what He doesn't know.</quote>
  <quote author="Dorothea Brande">
		Act as if it were impossible to fail.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Bishop John Shelby Spong">The view of the cross as the sacrifice for the sins of the world is a barbarian idea based on primitive concepts of God and must be dismissed.</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin, Go here for more of his quotes.">In the bullshit department, the businessman can not hold a candle to a clergyman.  Cause I gotta tell you the truth, folks, when it comes to bullshit, big time, major league BULLSHIT, exaggerated claims, RELIGION! .... No contest, no contest!</quote>
  <quote author="Randall Terry">I want you to just let a wave of intolerance wash over you.  I want you to let a wave of hatred wash over you.  Yes, hate is good — Our goal is a Christian nation.  We have a Biblical duty.  We are called by God to conquer this country.</quote>
  <quote author="Cullen Hightower">
		Wisdom is what's left after we've run out of personal opinions.
	</quote>
  <quote author="David Hume, An Enquiry Concerning Human Understanding, 1748">... The Christian religion not only was at first attended with miracles, but even at this day cannot be believed by any reasonable person without one.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison">It degrades from the equal rank of Citizens all those whose opinions in Religion do not bend to those of the Legislative authority.  Distant as it may be in its present form from the Inquisition, it differs from it only in degree.</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin, on his website">Praying is begging for an unseen deity to alter the laws of nature for someone admittedly unworthy.</quote>
  <quote author="Pablo Picasso (1881 - 1973)">
		Everything you can imagine is real.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Winston Churchill (1874 - 1965), Hansard, November 11, 1947">
		Many forms of Government have been tried, and will be tried in this world of sin and woe. No one pretends that democracy is perfect or all-wise. Indeed, it has been said that democracy is the worst form of government except all those other forms that have been tried from time to time.
	</quote>
  <quote author="David Condo, Maryland State Director for American Atheists">These attempts to turn courthouses into pulpits will continue to be challenged with facts and defeated with reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Herb Caen, The San Francisco Chronicle">The trouble with born-again Christians is that they are an even bigger pain the second time around.</quote>
  <quote author="Mahatma Gandhi (1869 - 1948)">
		It is unwise to be too sure of one's own wisdom. It is healthy to be reminded that the strongest might weaken and the wisest might err.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Bailey Smith, Christian Coalition">With all due respect to those dear people, my friend, God almighty does not hear the prayer of a Jew.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Thomas">Fundamentalists of different religions have more in common with each other than they do with the moderates of their own religions.</quote>
  <quote author="Lemuel Washburn">When religion comes in at the door, common sense goes out at the window</quote>
  <quote author="Calvin, Calvin &amp; Hobbes">It's hard to be religious when certain people are never incinerated by bolts of lightning.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen J. Gould, Dinosaur in a Haystack">The most important scientific revolutions all include, as their only common feature, the dethronement of human arrogance from one pedestal after another of previous convictions about our centrality in the cosmos.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, The Gods, 1872">It has always seemed to me that a being coming from another world, with a message of infinite importance to mankind, should at least have verified that message by his own signature.  Is it not wonderful that not one word was written by Christ?</quote>
  <quote author="Elizabeth Cady Stanton">The bible teaches that women brought sin and death into the world.  I don't believe that any man ever talked with god.  The bible was written by man out of his love of domination.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">In childhood our credulity serves us well.  It helps us to pack, with extraordinary rapidity, our skulls full of the wisdom of our parents and our ancestors.  But if we don't grow out of it in the fullness of time, our ... nature makes us a sitting target for astrologers, mediums, gurus, evangelists, and quacks.  We need to replace the automatic credulity of childhood with the constructive skepticism of adult science.</quote>
  <quote author="George Carlin">Religion convinced the world that there's an invisible man in the sky who watches everything you do.  And there's 10 things he doesn't want you to do or else you'll go to a burning place with a lake of fire until the end of eternity.  But he loves you! ... And he needs money!  He's all powerful, but he can't handle money!</quote>
  <quote author="A. A. Milne">The Old Testament is responsible for more atheism, agnosticism, disbelief — call it what you will — than any book ever written; it has emptied more churches than all the counterattractions of cinema, motor bicycle and golf course.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein (1879 - 1955), 'Treasury for the Free World,' 1946">
		It is the duty of every citizen according to his best capacities to give validity to his convictions in political affairs.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Luther, Erlangen Edition v. 16, pp. 142-148">Reason is the Devil's greatest whore; by nature and manner of being she is a noxious whore; she is a prostitute, the Devil's appointed whore; whore eaten by scab and leprosy who ought to be trodden under foot and destroyed, she and her wisdom ...  Throw dung in her face to make her ugly.  She is and she ought to be drowned in baptism...  She would deserve, the wretch, to be banished to the filthiest place in the house, to the closets.</quote>
  <quote author="Lemuel Washburn">What a queer thing is Christian salvation!  Believing in firemen will not save a burning house; believing in doctors will not make one well, but believing in a savior saves men.  Fudge!</quote>
  <quote author="George Santayana (1863 - 1952)">
		The wisest mind has something yet to learn.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">All religious beliefs seem weird to people not brought up in them.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, letter to William Bradford, 1771">Religious bondage shackles and debilitates the mind and unfits it for every noble enterprise.</quote>
  <quote author="from the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution">Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof;...</quote>
  <quote author="Rick Warren, minister">When Jesus stretched his arms wide on the cross, he was saying, 'I love you this much.'</quote>
  <quote author="Wallace v. Jaffree, 472 U.S. 38 (June 4, 1985) at 52-54, taken from Newdow vs. Congress (9th Circuit #00-16423).">[T]he Court has unambiguously concluded that the individual freedom of conscience protected by the First Amendment embraces the right to select any religious faith or none at all.  This conclusion derives support . . . from recognition of the fact that the political interest in forestalling intolerance extends beyond intolerance among Christian sects — or even intolerance among 'religions' — to encompass intolerance of the disbeliever and the uncertain.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">Most people are bothered by those passages of Scripture they do not understand, but the passages that bother me are those I do understand.</quote>
  <quote author="Cyril Connolly (1903 - 1974), &quot;The Unquiet Grave&quot;, 1945">
		Everything is a dangerous drug except reality, which is unendurable.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Katharine Hepburn (1909 - 2003) American Actress, Ladies' Home Journal, October 1991, from 2000 Years of Disbelief, James A. Haught, ed.">I'm an Atheist, and that's it.  I believe there's nothing we can know except that we should be kind to each other and do what we can for other people.</quote>
  <quote author="Phillip K. Dick">Reality is that which, when you stop believing in it, doesn't go away.</quote>
  <quote author="Martin Esslin">The dignity of man lies in his ability to face reality in all its meaninglessness.</quote>
  <quote author="Brent Allsop">Imagine encouraging a child to participate in such 'twisted' rituals and worshiping of tortuous crucifixes and such like this from birth.  No wonder we have so many hateful and sadistic people in our society.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">He who is involved in ecstacies and visions, who takes dreams for reality, and his own imagination for prophesy, is a fanatical novice of great hope and promise, and will soon advance to the higher stage and kill men for the love of God.</quote>
  <quote author="Quentin Crisp">
		If at first you don't succeed, failure may be your style.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Stuart Mill (1806 - 1873)">
		One person with a belief is equal to a force of 99 who have only interests.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Pope Innocent III, to his troops in the Albigensian Crusade of 1209">Kill them all, for God knows His own.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">If a man would follow, today, the teachings of the Old Testament, he would be a criminal.  If he would follow the teachings of the new, he would be insane.</quote>
  <quote author="Voltaire">You will notice that in all disputes between Christians since the birth of the Church, Rome has always favored the doctrine which most completely subjugated the human mind and annihilated reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Unknown">
		A wise man can see more from the bottom of a well than a fool can from a mountain top .
	</quote>
  <quote author="Bishop John Shelby Spong">The hope for life after death must be separated forever from the behavior control mentality of reward and punishment.  The Church must abandon, therefore, its reliance on guilt as a motivator of behavior.</quote>
  <quote author="Francis Bacon, quoted in 2000 Years of Disbelief by James A. Haught">The general root of superstition is that men observe when things hit, and not when they miss, and commit to memory the one, and pass over the other.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">On the dogmas of religion, as distinguished from moral principles, all mankind, from the beginning of the world to this day, have been quarreling, fighting, burning and torturing one another, for abstractions unintelligible to themselves and to all others, and absolutely beyond the comprehension of the human mind.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Heinlein, Notebooks of Lazarus Long, see here for more Heinlein quotes.">God is omnipotent, omniscient, and omnibenevolent — it says so right here on the label.  If you have a mind capable of believing all three of these attributes simultaneously, I have a wonderful bargain for you.  No checks, please.  Cash and in small bills.</quote>
  <quote author="Henrik Ibsen (1828 - 1906)">
		The great secret of power is never to will to do more than you can accomplish.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Aristotle (384 BC - 322 BC), Politics">
		If liberty and equality, as is thought by some are chiefly to be found in democracy, they will be best attained when all persons alike share in the government to the utmost.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Louis Stevenson (1850 - 1894)">
		Politics is perhaps the only profession for which no preparation is thought necessary.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Bill O'Reilly, conservative TV and radio host">There are a lot of very brilliant scholars who believe the reason we have incomplete science on evolution is that there is a higher power involved in this.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, First Inaugural Address">Let us reflect that, having banished from our land that religious intolerance under which mankind so long bled and suffered, we have yet gained little if we countenance a political intolerance as despotic, as wicked, and capable of as bitter and bloody persecutions.  Sometimes it is said that man cannot be trusted with the government of himself.  Can he, then, be trusted with the government of others?  Or have we found angels in the forms of kings to govern him?  Let history answer this question.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken (American Mercury, March 1930)">The most curious social convention of the great age in which we live is the one to the effect that religious opinions should be respected.</quote>
  <quote author="Reverend Jerry Falwell">AIDS is not just God's punishment for homosexuals; it is God's punishment for the society that tolerates homosexuals.</quote>
  <quote author="William Saroyan (1908 - 1981)">
		Good people are good because they've come to wisdom through failure.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Ronald Reagan (1911 - 2004)">
		Politics is supposed to be the second oldest profession. I have come to realize that it bears a very close resemblance to the first.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Canon Law 1369, enforced by The Catholic League for Religious and Civil Rights">A person is to be punished with a just penalty, who . . . utters blasphemy, or gravely harms public morals, or rails at or excites hatred of or contempt for religion or the Church.</quote>
  <quote author="Gloria Steinem">It's an incredible con job when you think of it, to believe something now in exchange for life after death.  Even corporations with all their reward systems don't try to make it posthumous.</quote>
  <quote author="Michel Eyquem, seigneur de Montaigne. (1533 - 1592)">Nothing is so firmly believed as what we least know.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Thomas">The essence of Christianity, as I see it, is love.  The essence of Humanism (and I'm also a Humanist) is love.  At that level, we're not far apart.</quote>
  <quote author="Baron d'Holbach (1723-1789) System of Nature">If we go back to the beginning we shall find that ignorance and fear created the gods; that fancy, enthusiasm, or deceit adorned or disfigured them; that weakness worships them; that credulity preserves them, and that custom, respect and tyranny support them in order to make the blindness of men serve its own interests.  If the ignorance of nature gave birth to the gods, the knowledge of nature is calculated to destroy them.</quote>
  <quote author="Anne Lamott">You can tell you have created God in your own image when it turns out that he or she hates all the same people you do.</quote>
  <quote author="Stewart L. Udall (1920 - ), commencement address, Dartmouth College, June 13, 1965">
		We have, I fear, confused power with greatness.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Adolf Hitler, to Gen. Gerhard Engel, 1941. Here are more of his quotes.">I am now as before a Catholic and will always remain so.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen J. Gould">Odd arrangements and funny solutions are the proof of evolution — paths that a sensible God would never tread but that a natural process, constrained by history, follows perforce.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine, ibid.">It is necessary to the happiness of man that he be mentally faithful to himself.  Infidelity does not consist in believing, or in disbelieving; it consists in professing to believe what one does not believe.  It is impossible to calculate the moral mischief, if I may so express it, that mental lying has produced in society.  When man has so far corrupted and prostituted the chastity of his mind, as to subscribe his professional belief to things he does not believe, he has prepared himself for the commission of every other crime.</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, ibid.">The belief in eternal torment, still subscribed to by fundamentalist Christian denominations, undoubtedly ranks as the most vicious and reprehensible doctrine of classical Christianity.  It has resulted in an incalculable amount of psychological torture, especially among children where it is employed as a terror tactic to prompt obedience.</quote>
  <quote author="Anna Eleanor Roosevelt (1884-1962) American diplomat, writer, and First Lady of the United States (1933-1945) letter to Cardinal Spellman, July 23, 1949, from The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom, Albert J. Menendez and Edd Doerr">Anyone who knows history will recognize that the domination of education or of government by any one particular religious faith is never a happy arrangement for the people.</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Winston Churchill">One day President Roosevelt told me that he was asking publicly for suggestions about what the war should be called. I said at once 'The Unnecessary War'. </quote>
  <quote author="Ken Ham, in The Lie – Evolution">I did not know from a scientific perspective why I did not believe in evolution – but I knew from a Biblical perspective it had to be wrong or my faith was in trouble.</quote>
  <quote author="Lord Macaulay, review of Lucy Aikin, 'Life and Writings of Addison,' 1943">
		The highest proof of virtue is to possess boundless power without abusing it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Douglas Adams, author of The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy">Isn't it enough to see that a garden is beautiful without having to believe that there are fairies at the bottom of it too?</quote>
  <quote author="Homer (800 BC - 700 BC), The Iliad">
		The single best augury is to fight for one's country.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Epicurus">Why should I fear death?  If I am, death is not.  If death is, I am not.  Why should I fear that which can only exist when I do not?</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin">Lighthouses are more helpful than churches.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin">As to Jesus of Nazareth, my Opinion of whom you particularly desire, I think the System of Morals and his Religion...has received various corrupting Changes, and I have, with most of the present dissenters in England, some doubts as to his Divinity.</quote>
  <quote author="Randy K. Milholland, Midnight Macabre, 10-18-05">
		We all have a few failures under our belt. It's what makes us ready for the successes.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Anon.">If you are comfortable with a lie, you will never look for the truth.</quote>
  <quote author="Pope John Paul II Roman Catholic Pontiff, revising Pius IX's Encyclical and substantially updating the Church's position on the teaching of evolution in an Address to the Pontifical Academy of Sciences (October 28, 1986), quoted from Victor J. Stenger, Has Science Found God? (2001)">Today, almost half a century after the publication of the Encyclical [of Pius IX], new knowledge has led to the recognition in the theory of evolution of more than a hypothesis.  It is indeed remarkable that this theory has been progressively accepted by researchers, following a series of discoveries in various fields of knowledge.  The convergence, neither sought nor fabricated, of the results of work that was conducted independently is in itself a significant argument in favor of this theory.</quote>
  <quote author="Edmund Burke">The only thing necessary for the triumph of evil is for good men to do nothing.</quote>
  <quote author="Bishop John Shelby Spong">The virgin birth, understood as literal biology, makes Christ's divinity, as traditionally understood, impossible.</quote>
  <quote author="Huntington F. Willard of Duke University, author of the textbook Genetics in Medicine, Director of the Institute for Genome Sciences and Policy">Evolution lies at the heart of biology.  It is seamlessly and continuously linked to health research to better understand such conditions as AIDS or bird flu or Parkinson's or cancer or heart disease.  Every biomedical experiment, every tiny advance, every major breakthrough ultimately connects to the principles first postulated by Darwin.</quote>
  <quote author="Euripides (ca. 480-406 B.C.E.) Greek poet, playwright and philospher">Talk sense to a fool and he calls you foolish.</quote>
  <quote author="Marquis de Sade">The idea of God is the sole wrong for which I cannot forgive mankind.</quote>
  <quote author="Mikhail Bakunin">People go to church for the same reasons they go to a tavern: to stupefy themselves, to forget their misery, to imagine themselves, for a few minutes anyway, free and happy.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine, ibid.">Is it more probable that nature should go out of her course, or that a man should tell a lie?  We have never seen, in our time, nature go out of her course; but we have good reason to believe that millions of lies have been told in the same time; it is, therefore, at least millions to one, that the reporter of a miracle tells a lie.</quote>
  <quote author="Ed Kerbs">The world is divided into armed camps, ready to commit genocide just because we can not agree on which fairy tales to believe.  In the end, religion will kill us all.</quote>
  <quote author="Joseph Lewis, in his 1930 speech Atheist Rises Above Creeds">Atheism rises above creeds and puts Humanity upon one plane.
There can be no 'chosen people' in the Atheist philosophy.
There are no bended knees in Atheism;
No supplications, no prayers;
No sacrificial redemptions;
No 'divine' revelations;
No washing in the blood of the lamb;
No crusades, no massacres, no holy wars;
No heaven, no hell, no purgatory;
No silly rewards and no vindictive punishments;
No christs, and no saviors;
No devils, no ghosts and no gods.</quote>
  <quote author="Ethan Allen (1738-1789) American Revolutionary, Reason the Only Oracle of Man (1784)">In those parts of the world where learning and science have prevailed, miracles have ceased; but in those parts of it as are barbarous and ignorant, miracles are still in vogue.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, The Truth Seeker">Every church that has a standard higher than human welfare is dangerous.</quote>
  <quote author="Jae Marston">Why is that people are quick to label Roman gods and goddesses as myth seeded from lack of understanding, while entertaining their own theological beliefs that are based on the same fear and ignorance?</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Maher, fired from ABC for telling the truth">We are a nation that is unenlightened because of religion.  I think religion stops people from thinking.  I think it justified crazies.  I think flying planes into a building was a faith-based initiative.  I think religion is a neurological disorder..</quote>
  <quote author="Saul Arinsky">Because life is there ahead of you and either one tests onself in its challenges or huddles in the valleys in a dreamless day-to-day existence whose only purpose is the preservation of an illusory security and safety.</quote>
  <quote author="Sinclair Lewis">When fascism comes to America, it will be wrapped in the flag, carrying a cross.</quote>
  <quote author="Ambrose Bierce">A prejudice is a vagrant opinion without visible means of support.</quote>
  <quote author="Herbert Bayard Swope (1882 - 1958)">
		I can't give you a sure-fire formula for success, but I can give you a formula for failure: try to please everybody all the time.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">If the man doesn't believe as we do, we say he is a crank, and that settles it.  I mean, it does nowadays, because now we can't burn him.</quote>
  <quote author="Immanuel Kant (1724 - 1804)">
		Science is organized knowledge. Wisdom is organized life.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Steven Weinberg, Nobel laureate physicist, A Designer Universe?">One of the great achievements of science has been, if not to make it impossible for intelligent people to be religious, then at least to make it possible for them not to be religious.  We should not retreat from this accomplishment.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">In God We Trust.  It is the choicest compliment that has ever been paid us, and the most gratifying to our feelings.  It is simple, direct, gracefully phrased; it always sounds well — In God We Trust.  I don't believe it would sound any better if it were true.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas A. Edison (1847 - 1931)">
		Many of life's failures are people who did not realize how close they were to success when they gave up.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Woody Allen">To YOU I'm an Atheist; to God, I'm the Loyal Opposition.</quote>
  <quote author="Carl Sagan">For me, it is far better to grasp the Universe as it really is than to persist in delusion, however satisfying and reassuring.</quote>
  <quote author="Eric Hoffer (1902 - 1983), The Passionate State of Mind, 1954">
		It is when power is wedded to chronic fear that it becomes formidable.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Robert F. Kennedy (1925 - 1968), 'I Remember, I Believe,' The Pursuit of Justice, 1964">
		The problem of power is how to achieve its responsible use rather than its irresponsible and indulgent use - of how to get men of power to live for the public rather than off the public.
	</quote>
  <quote author="James D. Watson, Nobel laureate, co-discoverer of the molecular structure of DNA">One of the greatest gifts science has brought to the world is continuing elimination of the supernatural.</quote>
  <quote author="Gordon Stein">The Age of Reason was responsible for making more people into infidels than any other book except the Bible.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert Owen, reformer and philanthropist">Finding that no religion is based on facts and cannot therefore be true, I began to reflect what must be the condition of mankind trained from infancy to believe in errors.</quote>
  <quote author="Joseph Addison (1672 - 1719), &quot;Cato&quot;, Act 4, Scene 4, 1713">
		How beautiful is death, when earn'd by virtue!Who would not be that youth? What pity is itThat we can die but once to serve our country!
	</quote>
  <quote author="Justice Louis D. Brandeis, 1927, Whitney v. California">Fear of serious injury alone cannot justify oppression of free speech and assembly.  Men feared witches and burnt women.  It is the function of speech to free men from the bondage of irrational fears.</quote>
  <quote author="Tom DeLay (R-TX), Majority Leader of the U.S. House of Representatives">He [God] is using me, all the time, everywhere, to stand up for a biblical worldview in everything that I do and everywhere I am.  He is training me.</quote>
  <quote author="Margaret Mead (1901-1978) American anthropologist, Redbook magazine, February, 1963, from Albert J. Menendez and Edd Doerr, The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">We will be a better country when each religious group can trust its members to obey the dictates of their own religious faith without assistance from the legal structure of the country.</quote>
  <quote author="Reverend Jerry Falwell">Leftist organizations are aggressively attempting to redefine America in their own Godless image.</quote>
  <quote author="Charles Caleb Colton (1780 - 1832), Lacon, 1825">
		To know the pains of power, we must go to those who have it; to know its pleasures, we must go to those who are seeking it.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Hugo L. Black, ibid.">Neither a state nor the Federal Government can, openly or secretly, participate in the affairs of any religious organizations or groups and vice versa.  In the words of Jefferson, the clause against establishment of religion by law was intended to erect 'a wall of separation between church and state.'</quote>
  <quote author="John B. Hodges">If faith is 'believing what you are told', religious ethics is 'doing what you are told'.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, Which Way? (1884)">It may be that ministers really think that their prayers do good, and it may be that frogs imagine that their croaking brings spring..</quote>
  <quote author="Ralph Waldo Emerson (1803 - 1882), Journals, 1824">
		When a whole nation is roaring Patriotism at the top of its voice, I am fain to explore the cleanness of its hands and purity of its heart.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech The Limitations of Toleration">The time to be happy is now.  The place to be happy is here.  The way to be happy is to try to make others so.</quote>
  <quote author="John Stuart Mill">The invisible and the non-existent look very much alike.</quote>
  <quote author="David Hume, In The Natural History of Religion">Examine the religious principles which have, in fact, prevailed in the world, and you will scarcely be persuaded that they are anything but sick men's dreams.</quote>
  <quote author="Bill Maher on Larry King Live">So I'm sorry, I don't respect people who believe in religion.  I was religious when I was a kid.  We all had dumb stuff drilled into our head.  It doesn't mean when you get to be an adult you can't drill it out.  I tell you something else they drilled into my head when I was a kid, mercury in my cavities.  We found out later mercury is so bad we shouldn't even eat it when there is a trace of it in fish.  But it was drilled into my teeth.  So when I got older, I had it drilled out.  You can do the same thing with religion.  To talk about this terrorism situation without talking about religion is like talking about AIDS in America without talking about homosexuality.  You can do it; it will get you applause on Oprah; but it's not true.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson, Notes on the State of Virginia, 1787">Millions of innocent men, women and children, since the introduction of Christianity, have been burnt, tortured, fined, imprisoned; yet we have not advanced one inch towards uniformity.  What has been the effect of coercion?  To make one half of the world fools and the other half hypocrites.  To support roguery and error all over the world.</quote>
  <quote author="Scott Adams, creator of Dilbert">Nothing defines humans better than their willingness to do irrational things in pursuit of phenomenally unlikely payoffs.  This is the principal behind lotteries, dating and religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Alan Wolfe, director of the Boisi Center for Religion and Public Life at Boston College">To teach kids that creationism explains something about the world is no different than teaching them that the earth is flat.</quote>
  <quote author="Ernst Mayr">On the other hand, famous evolutionists such as Dobzhansky were firm believers in a personal God.  He would work as a scientist all week and then on Sunday get down on his knees and pray to God.  Frankly I’ve never been able to understand it because you would need two totally different compartments in your brain, one that deals with religion and the other with everything else.</quote>
  <quote author="Francis Crick, co-discoverer of the double helix structure of DNA">In the fullness of time, educated people will believe there is no soul independent of the body, and hence no life after death.</quote>
  <quote author="from The Treaty of Tripoli, written during the administration of President George Washington, signed by President John Adams and unanimously approved by the Senate in 1797.">The Government of the United States is not in any sense founded on the Christian religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">The few have appealed to reason, to honor, to law, to freedom, to the known, and to happiness here in this world.  The many have appealed to prejudice, to fear, to miracle, to slavery, to the unknown, and to misery hereafter.</quote>
  <quote author="A.J. Ayer">If 'god' is a metaphysical term, then it cannot be even probable that a god exists.  For to say that 'God exists' is to make a metaphysical utterance which cannot be either true or false.  And by the same criterion, no sentence which purports to describe the nature of a transcendent god can possess any literal significance.</quote>
  <quote author="Solomon Short">The only winner in the War of 1812 was Tchaikovsky </quote>
  <quote author="Lester B. Pearson (1897 - 1972)">
		Politics is the skilled use of blunt objects.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, Free Inquiry, Summer, 2002">We who are atheists are also a-fairyists, a-teapotists, and a-unicornists, but we don't have to bother saying so.</quote>
  <quote author="John Adams, letter to F.A. Van der Kamp, Dec. 27, 1816">As I understand the Christian religion, it was, and is, a revelation.  But how has it happened that millions of fables, tales, legends, have been blended with both Jewish and Christian revelation that have made them the most bloody religion that ever existed?</quote>
  <quote author="Otto Von Bismarck (1815 - 1898), remark, Aug. 11, 1867">
		Politics is the art of the possible.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Keats (1795 - 1821)">
		Don't be discouraged by a failure. It can be a positive experience. Failure is, in a sense, the highway to success, inasmuch as every discovery of what is false leads us to seek earnestly after what is true, and every fresh experience points out some form of error which we shall afterwards carefully avoid.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Galileo">I do not feel obliged to believe that the same God who has endowed us with sense, reason, and intellect has intended us to forgo their use.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Paine">The world is my country, all mankind are my brethren, and to do good is my religion.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Thomas, president and co-founder of Atheists of Silicon Valley">Most true believers, when faced with evidence that contradicts their beliefs, will hold on to those beliefs even more strongly.</quote>
  <quote author="Ann Coulter, conservative author">We should invade their countries, kill their leaders and convert them to Christianity.</quote>
  <quote author="Larry Darby of The Atheist Law Center, in a letter to Alabama Gov. Bob Riley, Jan. 22, 2005">Materialism is the worldview or term describing application of reason, science and the human experience in understanding the world around us and in making decisions or living our day-to-day lives, as opposed to faith, dogma, prayer or superstition, etc.  As materialists we conclude there is no god or higher power and we therefore declare ourselves to be atheists or people who live without theism or religion.  Modern materialism is rooted in the work of the pre-Socratic Greek philosopher Democritus (460-370 BCE), who is also known as the Father of Atomic Science.  Antonyms to materialism are spiritualism or immaterialism; the worldview of materialism is not to be confused with consumerism.  Atheism is a conclusion, not a religion or ideology.</quote>
  <quote author="Botanical Society of America">People who oppose evolution, and seek to have creationism or intelligent design included in science curricula, seek to dismiss and change the most successful way of knowing ever discovered.  They wish to substitute opinion and belief for evidence and testing.  The proponents of creationism/intelligent design promote scientific ignorance in the guise of learning.  As professional scientists and educators, we strongly assert that such efforts are both misguided and flawed, presenting an incorrect view of science, its understandings, and its processes.</quote>
  <quote author="Judith Hayes, The Happy Heretic!">All it takes for America to become a theocracy is for nonbelievers to do nothing.</quote>
  <quote author="Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller (1908-1979) Governor of New York (1959-1973), U.S. vice-president (1974-1977) Veto Message, May 13, 1972. Rockefeller vetoed a bill to repeal New York's 1970 abortion law. Quoted from Albert J. Menendez and Edd Doerr, The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">I do not believe it right for one group to impose its vision of morality on an entire society.</quote>
  <quote author="Ulysses S. Grant, 18th U.S. President, quoted in 2000 Years of Disbelief, James A. Haught, ed.">In 1850, I believe, the church property in the United States, which paid no tax, amounted to $87 million.  In 1900, without a check, it is safe to say, this property will reach a sum exceeding $3 billion.  I would suggest the taxation of all property equally.</quote>
  <quote author="Proverbs 22:6">Train up a child in the way he should go and when he is old he will not depart from it.</quote>
  <quote author="Steve Allen">It is not hardness of heart or evil passions that drive individuals to atheism, but rather a scrupulous intellectual honesty.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken (Minority Report, 1956)">The chief contribution of Protestantism to human thought is its massive proof that God is a bore.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken">All great religions, in order to escape absurdity, have to admit a dilution of agnosticism.  It is only the savage, whether of the African bush or the American gospel tent, who pretends to know the will and intent of God exactly and completely.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">Man is a marvelous curiosity... he thinks he is the Creator's pet... he even believes the Creator loves him; has a passion for him; sits up nights to admire him; yes and watch over him and keep him out of trouble.  He prays to Him and thinks He listens.  Isn't it a quaint idea.</quote>
  <quote author="James Madison, ibid.">The establishment of the chaplainship to Congress is a palpable violation of ... constitutional principles.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech How to Reform Mankind">Too much doubt is better than too much credulity.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln, Letters to Thurlow Weed, March 14, 1865">Men are not flattered by being shown that there has been a difference of purpose between the Almighty and them.</quote>
  <quote author="Carl Sagan &amp; David Hume">Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence.</quote>
  <quote author="Luis Buquel">God and Country are an unbeatable team; they break all records for oppression and bloodshed.</quote>
  <quote author="John B. Hodges">Intellectual honesty is a skill that has to be learned and a virtue that has to be practiced; it often requires you to accept unpleasant conclusions.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">Eternal punishment must be eternal cruelty, and I do not see how any man, unless he has the brain of an idiot, or the heart of a wild beast, can believe in eternal punishment.</quote>
  <quote author="Lord Acton, Letter to Bishop Mandell Creighton, 1887">
		Power tends to corrupt, and absolute power corrupts absolutely.
	</quote>
  <quote author="William Franklin Billy Graham (1918-) American religious leader.  Parade, Feb. 1, 1981, in The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">I don't want to see religious bigotry in any form.  It would disturb me if there was a wedding between the religious fundamentalists and the political right.  The hard right has no interest in religion except to manipulate it.</quote>
  <quote author="James Feibleman">A myth is a religion in which no one any longer believes.</quote>
  <quote author="Dr. Ali Sina, in his review of Why I Am Not A Muslim">Islam is the enemy of science, of freethinking, of reason and of human rights.  It acts as a powerful break on the advancement of civilization.</quote>
  <quote author="Theodosius Dobzhansky, one of the founders of the modern synthesis of evolutionary theory">Nothing in biology makes sense except in the light of evolution.</quote>
  <quote author="The Rev. Raymond Lawrence, director of pastoral care at a New York hospital">There's no way to put God to the test, and that's exactly what you're doing when you design a study to see if God answers your prayers.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell (1872-1970)">We may define faith as the firm belief in something for which there is no evidence.  Where there is evidence, no one speaks of faith.  We do not speak of faith that two and two are four or that the earth is round.  We only speak of faith when we wish to substitute emotion for evidence.  The substitution of emotion for evidence is apt to lead to strife, since different groups, substitute different emotions.</quote>
  <quote author="Marcel Proust (1871 - 1922)">
		We don't receive wisdom; we must discover it for ourselves after a journey that no one can take for us or spare us.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">I am against religion because it teaches us to be satisfied with not understanding the world.</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll, in his speech Heresies and Heretics">Heresy is a cradle; orthodoxy is a coffin.</quote>
  <quote author="Aristotle (384 BC - 322 BC), Politics">
		Man is by nature a political animal.
	</quote>
  <quote author="manifesto of Ansar al-Sunnah (Iraq terrorist group)">We believe democracy is an Atheist call that idolizes human beings.</quote>
  <quote author="John Kerry">I can't take my Catholic belief, my article of faith, and legislate it on a Protestant or a Jew or an Atheist.  We have separation of church and state in the United States of America.</quote>
  <quote author="Stephen Vincent Benet (1898 - 1943), Litany for Dictatorships, 1935">
		We thought, because we had power, we had wisdom.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">The so-called Christian nations are the most enlightened and progressive ... but in spite of their religion, not because of it.  The Church has opposed every innovation and discovery from the day of Galileo down to our own time, when the use of anesthetic in childbirth was regarded as a sin because it avoided the biblical curse pronounced against Eve.  And every step in astronomy and geology ever taken has been opposed by bigotry and superstition.  The Greeks surpassed us in artistic culture and in architecture five hundred years before Christian religion was born.</quote>
  <quote author="Theodore Roosevelt, 26th U.S. President, October 12, 1915, from The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom, Albert J. Menendez and Edd Doerr">I hold that in this country there must be complete severance of Church and State; that public moneys shall not be used for the purpose of advancing any particular creed; and therefore that the public schools shall be nonsectarian and no public moneys appropriated for sectarian schools.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin, Poor Richard's Almanack, 1758">The way to see by Faith is to shut the eye of Reason.</quote>
  <quote author="Sir Leslie Stephen, Essays on Freethinking and Plainspeaking">The division between faith and reason is a half-measure, till it is frankly admitted that faith has to do with fiction, and reason with fact.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">I cannot see how a man of any large degree of humorous perception can ever be religious — unless he purposely shut the eyes of his mind &amp; keep them shut by force.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson (1743 - 1826), letter to John Melish, January 13, 1813">
		An honest man can feel no pleasure in the exercise of power over his fellow citizens.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">Faith is believing what you know ain't so.</quote>
  <quote author="Mahatma Gandhi">I love your Christ.  It's just that so many Christians are so unlike your Christ.</quote>
  <quote author="H.L. Mencken">God is the immemorial refuge of the incompetent, the helpless, the miserable.  They find not only sanctuary in His arms, but also a kind of superiority, soothing to their macerated egos; He will set them above their betters.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Einstein, Religion and Science">A man's ethical behavior should be based effectually on sympathy, education, and social ties; no religious basis is necessary.  Man would indeed be in a poor way if he had to be restrained by fear of punishment and hope of reward after death.</quote>
  <quote author="Alice Walker, Pulitzer Prize-winning author">What the mind doesn't understand, it worships or fears.</quote>
  <quote author="Beverly Sills (1929 - )">
		You may be disappointed if you fail, but you are doomed if you don't try.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Franklin">Revealed religion has no weight with me.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, River out of Eden">The universe that we observe has precisely the properties we should expect if there is, at bottom, no design, no purpose, no evil, no good, nothing but pitiless indifference.</quote>
  <quote author="Thomas Jefferson">Christianity is the most perverted system that ever shone on man.</quote>
  <quote author="George W. Bush, 43rd U.S. President, Easter Address of 2002">Americans practice different faiths in churches, synagogues, mosques and temples.  And many good people practice no faith at all.</quote>
  <quote author="H. L. Mencken (1880 - 1956)">
		Under democracy one party always devotes its chief energies to trying to prove that the other party is unfit to rule - and both commonly succeed, and are right.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">Nothing agrees with me.  If I drink coffee, it gives me dyspepsia; if I drink wine, it gives me the gout; if I go to church, it gives me dysentery.</quote>
  <quote author="Will Rogers">You can't say that civilization don't advance, however, for in every war they kill you in a new way. </quote>
  <quote author="Ronald Jenner, Postdoctoral Researcher, Marie Curie Fellow">Wherever science has not yet cast its illuminating light, the supernatural or metaphysical can and will always be unwrapped by some of us, to provide an explanation.</quote>
  <quote author="George H. Smith, ibid.">I am arguing that faith as such, faith as an alleged method of acquiring knowledge, is totally invalid and as a consequence, all propositions of faith, because they lack rational demonstration, must conflict with reason.</quote>
  <quote author="John F. Kennedy (1917-1963) 35th U.S. President (1961-1963) address to the Ministerial Association of Greater Houston, September 12, 1960, from Albert J. Menendez and Edd Doerr, The Great Quotations on Religious Freedom">I believe in an America where religious intolerance will someday end ... where every man has the same right to attend or not attend the church of his choice.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">I have never let schooling interfere with my education.</quote>
  <quote author="American Association of Physics Teachers">Evolution and cosmology represent two of the unifying concepts of modern science.  There are few scientific theories more firmly supported by observations than these ... We do our children a grave disservice if we remove from their education an exposure to firm scientific evidence supporting principles that significantly shape our understanding of the world in which we live.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell">The Christian religion, as organized in its churches, has been and still is the principal enemy of moral progress in the world..</quote>
  <quote author="Liza Minnelli (1946 - )">
		Reality is something you rise above.
	</quote>
  <quote author="James Huber">I'm a strong atheist.  I believe that gods are by definition supernatural beings, that the supernatural by definition violates natural law, violating natural law is by definition impossible, and impossible things by definition can't exist.</quote>
  <quote author="Will Rogers">Take the diplomacy out of war and the thing would fall flat in a week.</quote>
  <quote author="Mary Todd Lincoln, Lincoln's wife, in Toward The Mystery">My husband is not a Christian but is a religious man, I think.</quote>
  <quote author="Mark Twain">To trust the God of the Bible is to trust an irascible, vindictive, fierce and ever fickle and changeful master.</quote>
  <quote author="David Brin (1950 - )">
		It is said that power corrupts, but actually it's more true that power attracts the corruptible. The sane are usually attracted by other things than power.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins">There is no reason for believing that any sort of gods exist, and quite good reasons for believing that they do not exist and never have.  It has all been a gigantic waste of time and a waste of life.  It would be a joke of cosmic proportions if it weren't so tragic.</quote>
  <quote author="David Hume, Essays, Moral, Political and Literary (1741)">[priests are] the pretenders to power and dominion, and to a superior sanctity of character, distinct from virtue and good morals.</quote>
  <quote author="Bertrand Russell">So far as I can remember, there is not one word in the Gospels in praise of intelligence.</quote>
  <quote author="Franklin P. Adams (1881 - 1960), Nods and Becks (1944)">
		When the political columnists say 'Every thinking man' they mean themselves, and when candidates appeal to 'Every intelligent voter' they mean everybody who is going to vote for them.
	</quote>
  <quote author="John Lehman (1942 - ), Secretary of the Navy, 1981-1987">
		Power corrupts. Absolute power is kind of neat.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Ted Turner">Basically we are chimpanzees with about two percent more intelligence and a little less hair.</quote>
  <quote author="G. K. Chesterton (1874 - 1936)">
		"My country, right or wrong," is a thing that no patriot would think of saying except in a desperate case. It is like saying, "My mother, drunk or sober."
	</quote>
  <quote author="Ann Coulter, on Hannity &amp; Colmes, 6/20/01">God gave us the earth.  We have dominion over the plants, the animals, the trees.  God said, 'Earth is yours.  Take it.  Rape it.  It's yours.'</quote>
  <quote author="Duane Gish, in Evolution, The Fossils Say No! p. 42">We do not know how God created, what processes He used, for God used processes which are not now operating anywhere in the natural universe.  This is why we refer to divine creation as special creation.  We cannot discover by scientific investigations anything about the creative processes used by God.</quote>
  <quote author="President George W. Bush, February 2005">Faith-based organizations also need a guarantee they will not be forced to give up their right to hire people of their own faith as the price of competing for federal money.  If we want this program to be effective and to save lives, people have got to say interfacing with government will not cause me to lose my mission.</quote>
  <quote author="Richard Dawkins, in Lanny Swerdlow, My Short Interview with Richard Dawkins">You cannot be both sane and well educated and disbelieve in evolution.  The evidence is so strong that any sane, educated person has got to believe in evolution.</quote>
  <quote author="Friedrich Nietzsche, The Antichrist">So long as the priest, that professional negator, slanderer and poisoner of life, is regarded as a superior type of human being, there cannot be any answer to the question: What is Truth?</quote>
  <quote author="Robert G. Ingersoll">The intellectual advancement of man depends on how often he can exchange an old superstition for a new truth.</quote>
  <quote author="Marquis de Flers Robert and Arman de Caillavet">
		Democracy is the name we give the people whenever we need them.
	</quote>
  <quote author="Euripedes">I am the State</quote>
  <quote author="Kane">I am the Future</quote>
  <quote author="Bernard Bailey">When they discover the center of the universe, alot of people will be dissapointed to find they are not it.</quote>
  <quote author="Machiavelli">War ought to be the only study of a prince.</quote>
  <quote author="Marcel Proust">The voyage of discovery is not in seeking new landscapes but in having new eyes.</quote>
  <quote author="E. Rutherford">All science is either physics or stamp collecting.</quote>
  <quote author="Samuel Johnson">No government power can be abused long. Mankind will not bear it.</quote>
  <quote author="Calvin Coolidge">Civilization and profits go hand in hand.</quote>
  <quote author="Benjamin Disraeli">Free trade is not a principle, it is an expedient.</quote>
  <quote author="Andrew Marvell upon Oliver Cromwells return from Ireland">The inglorius arts of peace...</quote>
  <quote author="Will Durant">A great civilization is not conquored from without until it has destroyed itself from within.</quote>
  <quote author="Albert Eienstein">The most beautiful thing we can experience is the mysterious. It is the source of all true art and science.</quote>
  <quote author="General Douglas MacArthur">In war there is no substitute for victory.</quote>
  <quote author="Perseus">He who conquors, endures.</quote>
  <quote author="Abraham Lincoln">Nearly all men can stand adversity, but if you want to test a mans character give him power.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">A small mind is easily filled with faith.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">Prayer cleanses the soul, but Pain cleanses the body.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">Innocense proves nothing.</quote>
  <quote author="Book of the Astronomicon">What can a man know of the universe that knows not his own mind?</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">Blessed is the mind too small for doubt.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">In an hour of darkness, a blind man is the best guide. In an age of Insanity, look to the madman to show the way.</quote>
  <quote author="Scriptorus Munificatus">There can be no bystanders in the battle for survival. Anyone who will not fight by your side is an enemy you must crush.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">It is not the horrors of war that trouble me, but the unseen horrors of peace.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">A dagger in the dark is worth a thousand swords at dawn.</quote>
  <quote author="Anonymous">Hope is the first step on the road to dissapointment.</quote>
</quotes>